翻译: 死鱼
电波字幕组 诚心诚译
校对: Jodie
后期: 秋小豚
"香烟烙印"说明
电影导演大卫·芬奇将电影中提到的胶卷切换
时插入情节另外的一帧画面运用至电影本身
在电影中将其称之"香烟烙印" 因为一闪即过
以下将在"香烟烙印"出现之前2秒左右进行提示
最后一个烙印在片尾 不容错过
导演 大卫 · 芬奇
布拉德 · 皮特
爱德华 · 诺顿
海伦娜 · 博纳姆 · 卡特
搏击俱乐部
人们总在问我认不认识泰勒·德顿
People are always asking me if I know Tyler Durden.
还有三分钟
Three minutes.
尘埃落定 一切归零
This is it. Ground zero.
你要不要说两句来纪念这个伟大的时刻呢
Would you like to say a few words to mark the occasion?
嘴里塞着把枪 根本说不清话
With a gun barrel between your teeth, you speak only in vowels.
我想不到说什么
I can't think of anything.
有那么一会儿 我完全忘了泰勒的整个爆破拆除计划
For a second, I totally forget about Tyler's whole controlled demolition thing,
只想知道那把枪脏不脏
and I wonder how clean that gun is.
越来越刺激了
It's getting exciting now.
老话说 人总是会伤害自己爱的人
That old saying, how you always hurt the one you love,
其实人也会爱上自己伤害的人
well, it works both ways.
我们坐在最前排观赏这出毁灭大戏
We have front-row seats for this theater of mass destruction.
大破坏行动的爆破组
The Demolitions Committee of Project Mayhem
已经在12栋大楼的地基处放满了胶质炸药
wrapped the foundation columns of a dozen buildings with blasting gelatin.
两分钟后 始发炸药将引爆所有雷管药包
In two minutes, primary charges will blow base charges
若干街区瞬间化为废墟
and a few square blocks will be reduced to smouldering rubble.
我知道这些 因为泰勒他知道
I know this because Tyler knows this.
还有两分半钟 想想我们的成就吧
Two and a half. Think of everything we've accomplished.
忽然间 我意识到这一切
And suddenly I realize that all of this,
枪支 炸弹 革命
the gun, the bombs, the revolution,
都跟一个名叫玛拉辛格的女人有关
has got something to do with a girl named Marla Singer.
你好 我是
Bob
Bob Bob有对大奶子
Bob. Bob had bitch tits.
我们仍是男人
这是个睾丸癌患者互助会
This was a support group for men with testicular cancer.
这个鼻涕眼泪流我满身的大奶男 就是Bob
The big moosie slobbering all over me, that was Bob.
我们还是男人
We're still men.
没错 我们还是男人
Yes, we're men.
如假包换的男人
Men is what we are.
8个月前 Bob切除了睾丸并接受了激素治疗
Eight months age, Bob had his testicles removed. Then hormone therapy.
他的睾丸素水平太高 刺激了雌激素的分泌
He developed bitch tits because his testosterone was too high
导致他长了这对大奶子
and his body upped the estrogen.
我很舒服地
And that was where I fit...
他们又要给我胸部开刀排除积液了
They're gonna have to open up my pecs again and drain the fluid.
埋在这对大汗淋漓的巨乳之间 如此之大地垂在那儿
...between those huge sweating tits, that hung enormous,
让你觉得上帝的胸怀也不过如此
the way you'd think of God's as big.
好了 换你哭了
OK, you cry now.
等等 倒回去 让我从头说起
No, wait. Back up. Let me start earlier.
整整6个月 我都无法入睡
For six months, I couldn't sleep.
我睡不着
I couldn't sleep...
失眠让一切都亦真亦幻
With insomnia, nothing's real.
一切都飘忽遥远
Everything's far away.
"香烟烙印 1" 即将出现
一切都是重复 重复 再重复
Everything's a copy of a copy of a copy.
随着外太空探索的推进
When deep-space exploration ramps up,
所有天体都会用公司命名
it'll be the corporations that name everything.
IBM恒星
The IBM Stellar Sphere.
微软星系
The Microsoft Galaxy.
星巴克行星
The Planet Starbucks.
这周你得再出趟差 有急事要处理
I need you out of town a little more this week. We got some red flags to cover.
今天一定是周二 因为他系着菊蓝色领带
It must have been Tuesday. He was wearing his cornflower-blue tie.
你要我放下应该先做的报告  - 对
You want me to deprioritize my current reports...  - Yep.
等到你更急要的时候再做吗
...until you advise a status upgrade?
这才是你的首要"行动项目"
Make these your primary "action items".
这是你的飞机联票 路上有问题就给我打电话
Here's your flight coupons. Call me from the road if there's any snags.
他这么精力充沛 铁定是用拿铁灌肠了
He was full of pep. Must have had his grande latte enema.
和许多其他人一样 我已沦为购买
Like so many others, I had become a slave
宜家家居产品来筑巢的奴隶
to the IKEA nesting instinct.
- 呃 你好 我要订一套艾瑞卡佩卡里的防尘床裙  - 请稍等
- Eh, yes. I'd like to order the Erika Pekkari dust ruffles.  - Please hold.
只要看到设计巧妙的东西
If I saw something clever,
比如阴阳形状的咖啡桌
like a coffee table in the shape of a yin-yang,
我一定要买
I had to have it.
克丽丝个人办公组合
The Klipsk personal office unit.
哈福特莱克家用健身自行车
The Hovetrekke home exerbike.
或是丝锥牌绿色条纹罩单的欧汉莎沙发
Or the Ohamshab sofa with the Strinne green stripe pattern.
新上市
新最低价
甚至是用环保型本色纸张糊灯罩的里斯兰帕铁丝台灯
Even the Ryslampa wire lamps of environmentally-friendly unbleached paper.
我会一边翻着产品目录一边想
I'd flip through catalogues and wonder:
清仓
哪种餐具才能展现我的个人风格
What kind of dining set defines me as a person?
结果我全都买了 连带有小气泡瑕疵的玻璃盘子我都买了
I had it all. Even the glass dishes with tiny bubbles and imperfections,
说明它们是由正直淳朴勤劳的劳动人民手工制作的
proof that they were crafted by the honest, simple hard-working,
至于是哪里的劳动人民
indigenous peoples of...
- 请稍等  - 爱哪儿哪儿吧
- Please hold.  - ...wherever.
我等着呢
I was holding.
以前我们是看色情杂志
We used to read pornography.
现在看的是家居产品目录
Now it was the Horchow collection.
- 不 失眠症不会死人的  - 那嗜睡症呢
- No. You can't die of insomnia.  - What about narcolepsy?
我打了个盹儿 醒来却发现在陌生的地方 都不知道怎么过去的
I nod off, I wake up in strange places. I have no idea how I got there.
你得学会放松
You need to lighten up.
你就直接给我开点药不行吗
Can you please just give me something?
红红蓝蓝的吐诺尔 口红色的速可眠
Red and blue Tuinals, lipstick-red Seconals...
吐诺尔是一种镇定剂和催眠剂的混合药剂
不行 你需要的是健康自然的睡眠
No. You need healthy, natural sleep.
嚼点缬草根 多锻炼身体
Chew some valerian root and get more exercise.
- 嘿 拜托 我很痛苦啊  - 你这也算痛苦
- Hey, come on. I'm in pain.  - You wanna see pain?
周二晚上去趟第一卫理公会
Swing by First Methodist, Tuesday nights.
看看那些得了睾丸癌的人
See the guys with testicular cancer.
"香烟烙印 2" 即将出现
那才叫痛苦
That's pain.
我 我一直想要三个孩子
I... I always wanted three kids.
两个男孩儿一个女孩儿
Two boys and a girl.
你好 我是
Cornelius
Mindy想要两个女孩儿一个男孩儿
Mindy wanted two girls and a boy.
我们的意见从没统一过
We never could agree on anything.
她上礼拜生了第一个宝宝
Well, I... she like, she... She had her first child last week.
是个女孩儿
A girl.
和她
With... with her...
新任老公的
with her new husband.
其实我很感谢上帝
And thank God, you know?
我为她高兴
I'm... I'm glad for her.
因为这是她应得的
Be... because she deserves... it.
让我们谢谢Thomas分享他的故事
Everyone, let's thank Thomas for sharing himself with us.
谢谢你 Thomas
Thank you, Thomas.
我环视这个房间 看到了诸多勇气
I look around this room, and I see a lot of courage.
这给予了我力量
And that gives me strength.
我们互相给予力量
We give each other strength.
一对一的时间到了
It's time for the one-on-ones.
让我们在座的所有人都像Thomas那样敞开心扉吧
So let's all of us here follow thomas's good example and really open ourselves up.
"香烟烙印 3" 即将出现
请大家各自寻找搭档
Could you find a partner?
我就是这样认识大奶的
And this is how I met the big moosie.
他早已热泪盈眶
His eyes already shrink-wrapped in tears.
膝盖互相摩擦着 小碎步向我走来
Knees together. Those awkward little steps.
- 我叫Bob  - Bob
- My name is Bob.  - Bob?
Bob曾是健美冠军
Bob had been a champion bodybuilder.
你知道深夜的健胸电视节目吗
You know that chest expansion program you see on late-night TV?
就是他提的主意
That was his idea.
我用过禁药
I was a juicer.
就是用类固醇
You know, using steroids,
戴伯诺和
Diabonal and...
威斯特骆
Wisterol.
上帝啊 那些是用来打在赛马身上的
Oh, they use that on racehorses, for Christ's sakes.
现在我破产了
And now I'm bankrupt.
离婚了
I'm divorced.
我那两个长大了的孩子
My two grown kids...
甚至不肯回我电话
won't even return my phone calls.
这么坦白的陌生人让我不知所措
Strangers with this kind of honesty make me go a big, rubbery one.
该你了 Cornelius
Go ahead... Cornelius.
想哭就哭吧
You can cry.
然后 奇迹发生了
And then.. .something happened.
我释放了
I let go.
那感觉真的很好
That's really good.
迷失在虚无中
Lost in oblivion...
黑暗 宁静 又完整
dark and silent and complete.
我找到了自由
I found freedom.
失去一切希望就是自由
Losing all hope was freedom.
没关系的
It's OK.
婴儿都没我睡得沉
Babies don't sleep this well.
我变得
I became...
匿名戒酒会  "荣耀时刻"互助会  "逃离痛苦"互助会
乱伦幸存者互助会  匿名戒酒会
匿名戒酒会  "乐观积极"互助会  "展翅翱翔"互助会
上瘾了
addicted.
圣克里斯多夫圣公会
匿名戒酒会及其他互助会安排表
12 steps meetings 是非常著名的戒酒会12个步骤 均指匿名戒酒会
如何对抗肺结核
如果我一言不发 人们总会以为我的情况最糟
If I didn't say anything, people always assumed the worst.
清白自由
你好 我的名字叫
他们哭得越凶
They cried harder...
更高            更远
我就哭得越凶
then I cried harder.
互助会时间安排表
阿西西圣方济各宗教中心
皮肤癌      周一下午4:00-5:00
肾脏病      周二下午5:00-6:00
肝炎         周三下午6:00
胃癌         周五下午5:30-7:00
皮肤癌      周六日下午2:00-5:00
如有变化 请看教堂公告栏
现在让我们打开那扇绿门 你的心门
Now we're going to open the green door, the heart chakra...
我并非真的不久人世
I wasn't really dying.
也没有癌症或是寄生虫
I wasn't host to cancer or parasites.
我是被芸芸众生环绕的温暖小小中心
I was the warm little center that the life of this world crowded around.
将你遭受的痛苦想像成一个散发着治愈之光的白色光球
Imagine your pain as a white ball of healing light.
它在你身上游移 治疗着你
It moves over your body, healing you.
继续冥想 记得呼吸
Now keep this going. Remember to breathe.
现在向前走出房间的后门
And step forward through the back door of the room.
那道门通向何方呢
Where does it lead?
通向你的洞穴
To your cave.
向前迈进你的洞穴
Step forward into your cave.
就是这样
That's right.
你越来越深地走入你的洞穴
You're going deeper into your cave,
你会在那里找到
and you're going to find...
你的灵魂动物
your power animal.
滑呀
Slide.
每个晚上 我都会死一次
Every evening I died.
每个晚上 我又会重生
And every evening I was born again.
脱胎换骨
Resurrected.
Bob爱跟我搭档 因为他以为我也切除了睾丸
Bob loved me because he thought my testicles were removed too.
来到互助会 靠着他的奶子 准备放声哭泣
Being there, pressed against his tits, ready to cry.
这就是我的假期
This was my vacation.
但她
And she...
却毁了一切
ruined everything.
这里是癌症的 对吧
This is cancer, right?
这个妞儿 玛拉辛格 根本没得睾丸癌
This chick, Marla Singer, did not have testicular cancer.
她就是个骗子
She was a liar.
她根本什么病都没有
She had no diseases at all.
我在周四的"清白自由"血液寄生虫患者互助会上见过她
I had seen her at Free And Clear, my blood parasites group, Thursdays.
然后是每月两次的"希望"镰状细胞贫血症患者互助会
Then at Hope, my bimonthly sickle-cell circle.
接着是周五晚的"把握当下"肺结核患者互助会
And again at Seize The Day, my tuberculosis, Friday night.
玛拉 这个到处都去的女人
Marla, the big tourist.
她的谎言反映出我的谎言
Her lie reflected my lie.
突然间 我又失去了感觉
And suddenly, I felt nothing.
我哭不出来 所以再一次 我失眠了
I couldn't cry. So once again, I couldn't sleep.
"香烟烙印 4" 即将出现
下次互助会 引导冥想结束后
Next group, after guided meditation,
我们打开心门之后 开始拥抱的时候
after we open our heart chakras, when it's time to hug,
我要抓着玛拉辛格那贱人大喊
I'm gonna grab that bitch, Marla Singer, and scream:
玛拉 你个骗子 到处都去的贱人 我需要这个 快给我滚
Marla, you liar! You big tourist! I need this! Now, get out!
我已经四天没睡觉了
I hadn't slept in four days.
我们只要等它干了以后
We'll just let that dry...
当你得了失眠症 你永远无法真的睡着
When you have insomnia, you're never really asleep,
轻轻地刷
也永远无法真正清醒
and you're never really awake.
今晚的交流会 将由Chloe给我们做开场白
To begin tonight's communion, Chloe would like to say a few words.
对了 Chloe
Oh, yeah. Chloe.
Chloe就像是一具梅丽尔·斯特里普的骨架
Chloe looked the way Meryl Streep's skeleton would look
梅丽尔·斯特里普是美国著名女演员
至此电影放映之时 已获得9次奥斯卡最佳女主角提名 却只获奖1次
在颁奖派对上微笑走动 对每个人都倍加和善
if you made it smile and walk around the party being extra nice to everybody.
我还站在这里
Well, I'm still here.
虽然不知道还能有多久
But I don't know for how long.
也没人能给我个准确的答案
That's as much certainty as anyone can give me.
但我有个好消息
But I've got some good news.
面对死亡 我不再恐惧了
I no longer have any fear of death.
可是 我现在觉得好孤独
But... I am in a pretty lonely place.
没人愿意跟我上床
No one will have sex with me.
我的生命就快走到尽头 我只希望最后做一次爱
I'm so close to the end, and all I want is to get laid for the last time.
我家里准备了A片 还有润滑剂和春药
I have pornographic movies in my apartment, and lubricants and amyl nitrite.
谢谢你 Chloe
Thank you, Chloe.
让我们感谢Chloe
Everyone, let's thank Chloe.
谢谢你 Chloe
Thank you, Chloe.
现在 准备跟我进入冥想
Now, let's ready ourself for guided meditation.
你正站在你的洞穴的入口处
You're standing at the entrance of your cave.
你踏进洞穴里 慢慢走着
You step inside your cave and you walk...
如果真的长了肿瘤 我就叫它玛拉
If I did have a tumor, I'd name it Marla.
玛拉 就像你上膛处的小划伤
Marla, the little scratch on the roof of your mouth
只要你忍住不舔就会痊愈 但你就是忍不住
that would heal if only you could stop tonguing it, but you can't.
再走深入一点
...deeper into your cave as you walk.
你感到有一股治疗的能量环绕着你
You feel a healing energy in this place all around you.
现在找到你的灵魂动物
Now find your power animal.
滑呀
Slide.
好了 开始分组吧
OK. Let's partner up.
选一个今晚对你来说特别的人
Pick someone special to you tonight.
嘿
Hey.
- 我们得谈谈 - 好啊
- We need to talk.  - Sure.
- 我知道你的底细  - 什么
- I'm onto you.  - What?
没错 你就是个骗子 你根本不是快死了
Yeah. You're a faker. You're not dying.
你说什么
Sorry?
根据藏族哲学 或是西尔维娅·普拉斯的诗句 我们都终有一死
In the Tibetan-philosophy, Sylvia Plath sense of the word, I know we're all dying.
西尔维娅·普拉斯是一位重要的美国女诗人 自杀时年仅31岁
但你不是像Chloe那样真的要死了
But you're not dying the way Chloe back there's dying.
所以呢
So?
你什么互助会都参加 好嘛
So you're a tourist, OK?
我看到过你 黑素瘤患者互助会 肺结核患者互助会
I've seen you. I saw you at melanoma, I saw you at tuberculosis.
甚至在睾丸癌患者互助会还看到你
I saw you at testicular cancer!
看来你之前练过了吧
I saw you practising this.
- 练什么  - 数落我这一大段啊
- Practising what?  - Telling me off.
跟你希望的一样顺利吗 "Rupert"
Is it going as well as you hoped... "Rupert"?
- 我要去揭发你  - 去啊 我也会揭发你
- I'll expose you.  - Go ahead. I'll expose you.
好了 大家一起 哭出来吧
All right. Come together. Let yourselves cry.
老天 你为什么要这么做
Oh, God. Why are you doing this?
比看电影便宜 还有免费咖啡喝
It's cheaper than a movie and there's free coffee.
听着 这对我很重要 好吗
Look, this is important, OK?
这些是我的互助会 我已经参加一年多了
These are my groups. I've been coming here for over a year.
你又是为什么
Why do you do it?
不知道 人们以为你快死的时候
I don't know. When people think you're dying,
他们真的 真的会用心倾听你 而不是
they really, really listen to you instead of just...
不是充耳不闻 只等着轮到自己说话
Instead of waiting for their turn to speak.
是啊
Yeah.
没错
完全 彻底地打开你的心扉吧
Share yourself, completely.
听着 继续下去你会后悔的 这会上瘾
Look, you don't want to get into this. It becomes an addiction.
是嘛
Really?
我说真的 还有个骗子在我就完全哭不出来 而我需要哭
I'm not kidding. I can't cry if there's another faker at present, and I need this.
所以你就换个地方去吧
So you gotta find somewhere else to go.
去癌症病房当志愿陪聊呗 关我屁事
Candy-stripe a cancer ward. It's not my problem.
不 等等
No, wait a second.
别 别走
Hol... hold on.
这样吧 我们每周平分好了 淋巴瘤和肺结核都给你
I tell you, we'll split up the week, OK? You take lymphoma and tuberculosis.
肺结核你留着吧 我烟瘾太大
You take tuberculosis. My smoking doesn't go over at all.
好 没问题 那睾丸癌总没有争议吧
OK. Good. Fine. Testicular cancer should be no contest, I think.
严格意义来讲 我比你有资格去 你的睾丸还健在啊
Technically, I have more right to be there than you. You still have your balls.
- 你开玩笑呢吧  - 不知道 你看像吗
- You're kidding.  - I dunno. Am I?
不 不
No. No.
你到底想怎样
What do you want?
我想要寄生虫那俩
I'll take the parasites.
你不能两个都要 血液寄生虫给你好了
You can't have both the parasites, but why don't you take the blood parasites?
我要脑部寄生虫
I want brain parasites.
那我要血液寄生虫 但我要器质性脑痴呆
I'll take the blood, but I'm gonna take the organic brain dementia.
那个我要
I want that.
整个脑子总不能都归你吧
You can't have the whole brain.
现在你有四个 我只有两个
So far, you have four. I only have two.
好吧
OK.
寄生虫那俩都给你 我们都有三个了
Take both the parasites. They're yours. Now we both have three...
嘿 你有一半衣服没拿
Hey! You left half your clothes.
- 搞什么 你是拿来卖的  - 是的 我要卖几件衣服
- What, are you selling those?  - Yes, I'm selling some clothes.
那么 我们各有三个 一共六个了 第七天呢
So, we each have three. That's six. What about the seventh day?
我要肠癌
I want ascending bowel cancer.
这个女人下过一番功夫
The girl had done her homework.
不成 肠癌是我的
No. No. I want bowel cancer.
那也是你的最爱吗 跟我抢啊
That's your favorite too? Tried to slip it by me, eh?
这样 我们分了它吧
Look, we're gonna split it, OK?
每月第一个和第三个周日归你
Take the first and third Sunday of the month.
成交
Deal.
看来是要道别了
Looks like this is goodbye.
我们就别小题大做了吧
Well, let's not make a big thing out of it, OK?
你这样还没小题大做
How's this for not making a big thing?
嘿 玛拉 玛拉
Hey, Marla! Marla!
也 也许我们应该互相留个电话
May... maybe we should exchange numbers.
有必要吗
Should we?
万一我们想调换互助会时间呢
We might wanna switch nights.
好吧
OK.
我就是这么认识玛拉辛格的
This is how I met Marla Singer.
玛拉的人生哲学是她随时都可能会死
Marla's philosophy of life was that she might die at any moment.
她说 悲剧的是她一直都没死
The tragedy, she said, was that she didn't.
上面没有你的名字啊 你叫什么
It doesn't have your name! Who are you?
Cornelius Rupert 还是Travis
Cornelius? Rupert? Travis?
是你哪天晚上给的蠢名字吗
Any of the stupid names you give each night?
你在西雅图机场醒来
You wake up at SeaTac.
旧金山机场 洛杉矶机场
SFO. LAX.
芝加哥奥黑尔机场 达拉斯沃思堡机场 巴尔地摩华盛顿国际机场
You wake up at O'Hare. Dallas Fort Worth. BWI.
太平洋 山区 中部
Pacific. Mountain. Central.
不断变换时区
Lose an hour. Gain an hour.
先生 您乘坐的航班两小时后才开始办理登记手续
Check-in for that flight doesn't begin for another two hours, sir.
这就是你的人生 正一分一分地消逝
This is your life, and it's ending one minute at a time.
你在凤凰空港国际机场醒来
You wake up at Air Harbor International.
如果你在不同时间 不同地点醒来
If you wake up at a different time, in a different place,
你会变成一个不同的人吗
could you wake up as a different person?
不管到哪儿 我都过着渺小的生活
Everywhere I travel, tiny life.
单人份砂糖包 单人份奶油 一小块儿黄油
Single-serving sugar, single-serving cream, single pat of butter.
微波炉加热的法式蓝带航空套餐
The microwave cordon bleu hobby kit.
洗发护发旅行包
Shampoo-conditioner combos.
试用装漱口水 小块肥皂
Sample package mouthwash. Tiny bars of soap.
布里奇沃斯
豪华套房
我在每次航班遇到的人 也只是"一次性"的朋友
The people I meet on each flight, they're single-serving friends.
一颗薄荷糖感谢你
在起飞和降落间 我们共享一段时光 仅此而已
Between takeoff and landing, we have our time together. That's all we get.
布里奇沃斯
豪华套房
欢迎光临
Welcome!
在漫长时间轴上的某一点 每个人的存活率都会降为零
On a long-enough time line, the survival rate for everyone drops to zero.
我是一名汽车召回协调员 我的工作就是套用公式
I was a recall coordinator. My job was to apply the formula.
那婴儿就是从挡风玻璃飞出来的 这个三分
The infant went through the windshield. Three points.
我们公司产的一辆新车 时速96公里驶离某个地方的时候
A new car built by my company leaves somewhere traveling at 60mph.
后差速器突然锁死了
The rear differential locks up.
小孩的牙套还卡在后座的烟灰缸上
The teenager's braces are stuck to the backseat ashtray.
可以当个不错的戒烟广告
Might make a good anti-smoking ad.
整个车子玉石俱焚 所有困在里面的人都死了
The car crashes and burns with everyone trapped inside.
那么 我们应该召回这款车吗
Now, should we initiate a recall?
那爸爸一定很胖
The father must've been huge.
看到座位上脂肪烧过的痕迹吗 穿的是涤纶衬衫
See where the fats burned to the seat? The polyester shirt?
很有现代艺术感
Very modern art.
将这款车的售出量 A
Take the number of vehicles in the field, A.
乘以出故障的概率 B
Multiply it by the probable rate of failure, B.
再乘以庭外和解需要的平均费用 C
Then multiply the result by the average out-of-court settlement, C.
A乘以B乘以C
A times B times C...
等于X
equals X.
如果X小于召回成本 我们就不召回
If X is less than the cost of a recall, we don't do one.
这种意外很多吗
Are there a lot of these kinds of accidents?
多到你无法想象
You wouldn't believe.
你是哪家汽车公司的
Which car company do you work for?
很大的一家
A major one.
每次飞机起飞或降落转弯太急剧时
Every time the plane banked too sharply on takeoff or landing,
我都祈祷来个飞机坠毁或是空中撞击 什么都行
I prayed for a crash or a mid-air collision. Anything.
出差时意外死亡 人寿保险会赔三倍
Life insurance pays off triple if you die on a business trip.
禁止吸烟
请系好安全带
如果您坐在紧急出口旁边
If you are seated in an emergency exit row
并且您觉得自己无力或不愿履行
And feel you would be unable or unwilling to perform
安全卡上列明的义务
the duties listed on the safety card,
请向乘务人员要求换座位
please ask a flight attendant to reseat you.
紧急出口
看来你的责任很重
It's a lot of responsibility.
想要换座位吗
Wanna switch seats?
算了 我觉得我不适合做那份工作
No. I'm not sure I'm the man for that particular job.
三万英尺高的紧急出口
An exit-door procedure at 30,000 feet.
嗯哼
Mm-hm.
有什么安全可言
The illusion of safety.
对啊 我想也是
Yeah. I guess so.
知道为什么飞机上会有氧气罩吗
You know why they put oxzgen masks on planes?
让你能呼吸呗
So you can breathe.
是因为氧气会让你兴奋
Oxzgen gets you high.
碰到灾难性突发事故时 你会慌乱得大口喘气
In a catastrophic emergency, you take giant panic breaths.
吸了氧气你就突然镇定下来 接受现实
Suddenly you become euphoric, docile. You accept your fate.
都在这儿画着呢
It's all right here.
紧急水上降落 时速每小时966公里
Emergency water landing, 600 mph.
准备姿势
乘客们都面无表情 跟印度神牛一样镇定自若
Blank faces. Calm as Hindu cows.
你刚才说的 呃
That's, um...
理论很有趣
That's an interesting theory.
你是干什么的
What do you do?
什么意思
What do you mean?
你靠什么营生的
What do you do for a living?
问这干什么 你好假装有兴趣吗
Why? So you can pretend like you're interested?
好吧
OK.
你的笑中透着病态的绝望
You have a kind of sick desperation in your laugh.
我们的手提箱一模一样
We have the exact same briefcase.
肥皂
Soap.
什么
Sorry?
我是制造和销售肥皂的
I make and I sell soap.
这可是文明的准绳
The yardstick of civilization.
我就是这样认识了
And this is how I met...
泰勒·德顿
Tyler Durden.
你知道把等量的汽油和冰冻浓缩橙汁混合后
Did you know if you mix equal parts of gasoline and frozen orange juice concentrate,
能做成凝固汽油弹吗
you can make napalm?
- 不 我不知道 真的吗  - 是真的
- No, I did not that. Is that true?  - That's right.
用简单的日用品就能做出各种炸弹
One can make all kinds of explosives using simple household items.
真的假的
Really?
只要你想
If one were so inclined.
泰勒 你是我目前为止碰到的"一次性"朋友中最有趣的一个
Tyler, you are by far the most interesting single-serving friend I have ever met.
你看 飞机上所有东西都是一次性的
You see, everything on a plane is single-serving...
我懂了 很聪明
Oh, I get it. It's very clever.
谢谢
Thank you.
对你帮助大吗
How's that working out for you?
- 什么  - 聪明啊
- What?  - Being clever.
挺好的
Great.
那就继续保持吧 再接再厉
Keep it up, then. Keep it right up.
现在有个礼节问题 我经过的时候是屁股还是裆部对着你
Now, a question of etiquette. As I pass, do I give you the ass or the crotch?
我怎么会沦落到和泰勒住在一起呢
How I came to live with Tyler is...
航空公司对震动的行李有相关政策
Airlines have this policy about vibrating luggage.
它 它在滴答响吗
Was... was it ticking?
其实 丢手不担心嘀嗒声 因为现代炸弹不会嘀嗒了
Actually throwers don't worry about ticking, 'cause modern bombs don't tick.
机场安检
什么 丢手
Sorry. Throwers?
行李装运员
Baggage handlers.
但如果行李箱震动的话 他们就得报警
But when a suitcase vibrates, the throwers have to call the police.
我的行李箱震动了吗
My suitcase was vibrating?
十有八九是电动剃须刀 不过
Nine times out of ten it's an electric razor, but...
偶尔也会是个
every once in a while...
震动棒
it's a dildo.
当然公司规定如果是震动棒的话 我们不能透露其拥有者是谁
Of course it's company policy never to imply ownership in the event of a dildo.
我们只能说是"一个震动棒" 决不能说"你的震动棒"
We have to use the indefinite article, "a dildo", never, "your dildo".
我没有
I don't own...
我所有的东西都在那个手提箱里
I had everything in that suitcase.
我的CK衬衫 我的DKNY鞋 我的AX领带
My CK shirts. My DKNY shoes. My AX ties.
算了
Never mind.
嘿 那是我的车
Hey! That's my car!
皮尔森大厦
助你成为人上人
我家在一座公寓大厦的15楼 这里像是排列着
Home was a condo on the 15th floor of a filing cabinet
寡妇和年轻白领的档案柜
for widows and young professionals.
墙壁都是坚硬的混凝土
The walls were solid concrete.
当你的隔壁邻居摘下她的助听器 必须要用最大音量
A foot of concrete's important when your next-door neighbor
看游戏节目的时候 这一英尺的混硬土墙显得尤为重要
lets her hearing aid go and has to watch game shows at full volume.
或是当那些曾经属于你的
Or when a volcanic blast of debris
家具和私人物品被炸出你那全封闭的窗子
that used to be your furniture and personal effects
飞出的碎片发出火山般的咆哮在夜空中燃烧时 也是如此
blows out of your fully sealing windows and sails flaming into the night.
这种事在所难免吧
I suppose these things happen.
上面 什么都没有了
There's... nothing up there.
你不能进去 这是警方的命令
You can't go into the unit. Police orders.
你有可以求助的朋友吗
Do you have somebody you can call?
真丢人 一屋子的调味料却没有食物
How embarrassing. A house full of condiments and no food.
玛拉辛格
之后警方会跟我说 可能是常燃小火熄灭了
The police would later tell me that the pilot light might have gone out,
泄漏了一点儿天然气
letting out a little bit of gas.
这点儿天然气慢慢充满整个公寓
That gas could have slowly filled the condo.
这对于一个有着挑高屋顶的160平米房间要花上好几天
1700 square feet with high ceilings for days and days.
然后冰箱压缩机启动了
Then the refrigerator's compressor could have clicked on.
喂
Yeah?
我听到你呼吸了 你
I can hear you breathing, you...
珮波街肥皂公司
纯天然                                     手工制造
布拉德福德珮波街537号
你现在问我的话 我也说不上来为什么要打给他
If you ask me now, I couldn't tell you why I called him.
- 你好  - 谁啊
- Hello?  - Who's this?
泰勒吗
Tyler?
- 你是谁  - 呃
- Who is this?  - Um...
我们在飞机上见过
We met... we met on the airplane.
我们有一样的手提箱
We had the same suitcase?
- 呃 那个聪明人  - 噢 是你啊
- Uh... the clever guy.  - Oh... oh yeah. Right.
我刚给你打电话了 但没人接电话 我用的是公共电话
I called a second ago. There... there was no answer. I'm at a payphone.
对 我打*69查了刚打来的号码 我从来不接电话
Yeah, I *69'd you. I never pick up my phone.
在美国 拨打*69可以查到刚才给你打电话的号码
- 找我有事吗  - 呃
- So what's up?  - Uh...
那个
Well...
说了你也不会信
You're not gonna believe this.
卢的酒馆
酒
吧
老兄 这还不算糟的
You know, man, it could be worse.
有的女人还可能趁你睡觉的时候
A woman could cut off your penis while you sleep
割下你的老二扔出车外呢
and toss it out of the window of a moving car.
总是会这样
There's always that.
每次买家具的时候 你都告诉自己
I don't know, it's just... When you buy furniture, you tell yourself:
到此为止 这是我所需要的最后一个沙发
That's it. That's the last sofa I'm gonna need.
不管再发生什么 沙发的问题已经解决了
Whatever else happens, I've got that sofa problem handled.
我什么都买了 我有一套相当好的立体音响
I had it all. I had a stereo that was very decent.
一组高档体面的衣柜
A wardrobe that was getting very respectable.
我的人生就要完整了
I was close to being complete.
- 妈的 现在全没了  - 全没了
- Shit, man. Now it's all gone.  - All gone.
对 全没了
Yeah. All gone.
你知道羽绒被是什么吗
Do you know what a duvet is?
- 一种被子  - 一个铺盖 只是个铺盖而已
- A comforter.  - It's a blanket. Just a blanket.
为什么我们会知道羽绒被是什么
Why do guys like us know what a duvet is?
在原始狩猎者的世界中 难道它是生存的必需品吗
Is this essential to our survival in the hunter-gatherer sense of the world?
不是
No.
那我们是什么
What are we, then?
不知道 消费者吗
I dunno. Consumers.
没错 我们是消费者
Right. We're consumers.
我们是痴迷于时尚生活方式的副产品
We are by-products of a lifestyle obsession.
谋杀 犯罪 贫困 这些我都不关心
Murder, crime, poverty. These things don't concern me.
我关心的是名人杂志
What concerns me are celebrity magazines,
有500个频道的电视
television with 500 channels,
内衣裤上印着谁的名字
some guy's name on my underwear.
生发剂 伟哥 脱脂油
Rogaine. Viagra. Olestra.
- 还有玛莎·斯图尔特  - 去他妈的玛莎·斯图尔特
- Martha Stewart.  - Fuck Martha Stewart.
玛莎·斯图尔特是美国亿万富翁 也是名副其实的家政女王
她是在泰坦尼克号上擦铜器 都得沉到底 伙计
Martha's polishing the brass on the Titanic. It's all going down, man.
所以别他妈再管你的沙发组还有什么丝锥牌绿条纹沙发套了
So fuck off with your sofa units and Strinne green stripe patterns.
要我说 残缺的才是人生
I say never be complete.
别再追求完美
I say stop being perfect.
我说 让我们进化
I say let... let's evolve.
顺其自然 水来土掩
Let the chips fall where they may.
但这只是我个人观点 不一定正确
But that's me, and I could be wrong.
也许是场可怕的灾难
Maybe it's a terrible tragedy.
就 就是些身外物 不是什么灾难
It's.. it's just stuff. Not a tragedy...
你确实失去了很多现代生活的工具
Well, you did lose a lot of versatile solutions for modern living.
操 你说得对 不 我不抽烟
Fuck, you're right. No, I don't smoke.
保险公司应该会赔偿我的 所以
My insurance is probably gonna cover it, so...
怎么
What?
你已经被自己的财产奴役了
The things you own end up owning you.
不过随你吧 伙计
But do what you like, man.
很晚了
Oh, it's late.
- 嘿 谢谢你请我喝酒  - 没事 伙计
- Hey, thanks for the beer.  - Yeah, man.
我得找个旅馆才行
I should find a hotel.
- 哦  - 怎么了
- Oh!  - What?
什么
What?
- 找旅馆  - 是啊
- A hotel?  - Yeah.
直接开口啊 老兄
Just ask, man.
你说什么呢
What are you talking about?
拜托 都一起喝了三大扎啤酒 你还不敢问
Oh, God. Three pitchers of beer and you still can't ask.
- 什么  - 你给我打电话就是想找个地方住
- What?  - You called me 'cause you needed a place to stay.
- 嘿 不 我不是  - 就是 你开口就是了
- Oh, hey. No, no, no.  - Yes, you did. So just ask.
别客套了 直接说吧 伙计
Cut the foreplay and just ask, man.
会 会麻烦到你吗
Would... would that be a problem?
你开口会麻烦到吗
Is it a problem for you to ask?
- 我能到你家借住吗  - 好啊
- Can I stay at your place?  - Yeah.
谢谢
Thanks.
- 我要你帮我一个忙  - 好啊 当然可以
- I want you to do me a favor.  - Yeah, sure.
我要你用尽全力打我一拳
I want you to hit me as hard as you can.
什么
What?
我要你用尽全力打我一拳
I want you to hit me as hard as you can.
让我先介绍一下泰勒·德顿
Let me tell you a little bit about Tyler Durden.
泰勒是个夜猫子 我们睡觉的时候他却在工作
Tyler was a night person. While the rest of us were sleeping, he worked.
他的一个兼职是做电影放映师
He had one part-time job as a projectionist.
一部电影不是一大卷胶片 而是分了几卷
You see, a movie doesn't come all on one big reel. It comes on a few.
这就需要有人在一卷放完另一卷开始时
So someone has to be there to switch the projectors at the exact moment
准确切换放映机
that one reel ends and the next one begins.
仔细看的话
If you look for it,
你会在荧幕右上方看到这些小点
you can see these little dots come into the upper right hand corner of the screen.
用行话说叫香烟烙点
In the industry, we call them cigarette burns.
那就是换下一卷的提示
That's the cue for a changeover.
他切换了放映机 电影继续如常放映
He flips the projectors, movie keeps right on going,
观众们都毫不知情
and noboday in the audience has any idea.
怎么会有人想做这种烂工作
Why would anyone want this shit job?
因为这样他就能做怪
'Cause it affords him other interesting opportunities.
比如把一帧色情电影情节剪进家庭电影中
Like splicing a single frame of pornography into family films.
所以当名人配音的傲慢小猫
So when the snooty cat and the courageous dog
和勇敢小狗在第三胶卷中第一次碰面的时候
with the celebrity voices meet for the first time in reel three,
你将会看到泰勒的杰作在电影里一闪而过
that's when you'll catch a flash of Tyler's contribution to the film.
没有人会察觉自己看到了 但他们的确看到了
Nobody knows that they saw it but they did.
一根超级棒的大屌
Nice, big cock.
在本片片尾将会看到
泰勒的小动作快到没法察觉
Even a hummingbird couldn't catch Tyler at work.
泰勒有时也在普莱斯曼豪华大酒店做宴会服务员
Tyler also works sometimes as a banquet waiter at the luxurious Pressman Hotel.
他简直是食品服务业的游击恐怖份子
He was the guerrilla terrorist of the food service industry.
别看着我 我会尿不出来
Do not watch. I cannot go when you watch.
除了给龙虾浓汤加料外
Apart from seasoning the lobster bisque,
他还对着糕点放屁 朝红烩莴苣打喷嚏
he farted on meringues, sneezed on braised endives...
至于蘑菇汤里面的奶油嘛
and as for the cream of mushroom soup, well...
- 说啊 告诉他们  - 你们懂的
- Go ahead, tell 'em.  - You get the idea.
你想让我做什么 就打你一拳吗
What do you want me to do? You just want me to hit you?
来吧 就帮我这一个忙
Come on. Do me this one favor.
- 为什么  - 我也不知道为什么 从来没打过架 你呢
- Why?  - Why? I don't know why. I don't know. Never been in a fight. You?
没有 但 这是件好事啊
No. But that... that's a good thing.
才不是好事 从来没打过架 你能了解自己多少
No, it's not. How much can you know about yourself if you haven't been in a fight?
我可不想死的时候身上连个疤都没有
I don't wanna die without any scars.
来吧 快打我 趁我还有胆量
Come on. Hit me, before I lose my nerve.
- 天哪 这太疯狂了 我  - 那就疯一把 放马过来
- Oh, God. This is crazy. I...  - So go crazy! Let it rip.
- 我不确定  - 我也不确定
- I don't know about this.  - I don't either.
谁他妈的在乎啊 又没人看 你想那么多干嘛
Who gives a shit? No one's watching. What do you care?
慢着 真是疯了 你想让我打你
Wait. This is crazy. You want me to hit you?
没错
That's right.
打哪儿 打脸吗
Where? Like, in the face?
随便你
Surprise me.
这真是太他妈蠢了
This is so fucking stupid.
操他妈的
Motherfucker!
你居然打我耳朵
He hit me in the ear!
- 老天 对不起啊  - 嗷 天哪
- Well, Jesus, I'm sorry.  - Ow! Christ!
为什么打耳朵啊 老兄
Why the ear, man?
- 我搞砸了  - 不 简直完美
- I fucked it up.  - No, that was perfect.
不 没事
No, it's all right.
真的很疼啊
It really hurts.
是吧
Right.
再来一下
Hit me again.
不 换你打我了 来吧
No, you hit me. Come on!
我们应该找机会再打一架
We should do this again sometime.
珮  波  街
- 你的车呢  - 什么车
- Where's your car?  - What car?
我不知道泰勒怎么找到这个房子的
I don't know how Tyler found that house,
他说他已经住了一年了
but he said he'd been there for a year.
看上去就像个快被拆的危房
It looked like it was waiting to be torn down.
多数窗子都用木板封着
Most of the windows were boarded up.
自从警察还是谁破门而入后 前门就没装过锁
There was no lock on the front door from when the police, or whoever, kicked it in.
楼梯好像随时都会塌
The stairs were ready to collapse.
我不知道房子是他的还是他偷住的
I didn't know if he owned it or he was squatting.
哪个都不让我觉得意外
Neither would have surprised me.
就这儿 你的房间
Yep. That's you.
那个房间是我的 那是厕所 可以吧
That's me. That's the toilet. Good?
好 谢谢
Yeah, thanks.
什么狗窝
What a shithole.
所有东西都坏了
Nothing worked.
开这盏灯 屋里另一盏灯就会灭
Turning on one light meant another light in the house went out.
没有邻居 附近只有一些仓库和一家造纸厂
There were no neighbors. Just some warehouses and a paper mill.
蒸气的恶臭 烂木屑的腐朽味道
That fart smell of steam. The hamster-cage smell of wood chips.
嘿 那边什么情况
Hey. What have we here?
- 嘿 你们好啊  - 嘿
- Hey, guys.  - Hey.
一下雨 我们就得拉闸
Every time it rained, we had to kill the power.
一个月过去了 我都没想看电视
By the end of the first month, I didn't miss TV.
我甚至不在意那已经不制冷 难闻的破冰箱
I didn't even mind the warm, stale refrigerator.
下一个换我好吗
Can I be next?
没问题 兄弟
All right, man.
领带摘下来
Lose the tie.
夜晚 方圆半英里内只有我和泰勒
At night, Tyler and I were alone for half a mile in every direction.
雨水沿着石灰墙和灯架往下流
Rain trickled down through the plaster and the light fixtures.
木制的家具泡胀又收缩
Everything wooden swelled and shrank.
到处都是生锈的钉子 等着刺伤你的手肘
Everywhere were rusted nails to snag your elbow on.
之前的住户并不怎么出门
The previous occupant had been a bit of a shut-in.
- 嘿 伙计 看什么呢  - 听听这个
- Hey man, what are you reading?  - Listen to this.
这是篇以人体器官作第一人称写的文章
It's an article written by an organ in the first person.
"我是Jack的延髓
"I am Jack's medulla oblongata.
没有我 Jack将无法控制他的心率 血压或者呼吸"
Without me, Jack could not regulate his heart rate, blood pressure or breathing."
这样的文章有一整个系列
There's a whole series of these.
"我是Jill的乳头"
"I am Jill's nipples."
"我是Jack的结肠"
"I am Jack's colon."
呵呵 "我得了癌症 害死了Jack"
Yeah. "I get cancer. I kill Jack."
打架以后 你生活中其他一切事物的音量都减弱了
After fighting, everything else in your life got the volume turned down.
什么
What?
你可以应对所有问题
You could deal with anything.
那些报告写完了吗
Have you finished those reports?
如果你可以和任何人打 你想跟谁打
If you could fight anyone, who would you fight?
应该是跟我老板打
I'd fight my boss, probably.
是嘛
Really?
- 是啊 怎么了 你呢  - 我要跟我爸打
- Yeah. Why? Who would you fight?  - I'd fight my dad.
我都不记得我爸了
I don't know my dad.
我是说 我知道我爸 但
I mean, I know him, but...
我差不多六岁时 他就离开了
he left when I was, like, six years old.
娶了另一个女人 又生了孩子
Married this other woman and had some other kids.
他几乎每六年就得这么干一次
And he like did this every six years.
去新的城市 建立新的家庭
He goes to a new city and starts a new family.
这混蛋是在他妈的开连锁吧
Fucker's setting up franchises!
我爸没上过大学 所以就一定要我去读
My dad never went to college, so it was real important that I go.
听起来很耳熟
That sounds familiar.
所以毕业后我打长途问他 "爸 现在我干什么去"
So I graduate. I call him up long-distance and say, "Dad, now what?"
- 他说"找工作啊"  - 一样
- He says, "Get a job."  - Same here.
现在我25了 又打电话给他 "爸 现在呢"
Now I'm 25. Make my yearly call again. Say "Dad, now what?"
他说 "不知道 要不结婚吧"
He says, "I dunno. Get married. "
你哪儿能结婚啊
You can't get married.
我还是个30岁的大男孩
I'm a 30-year-old boy.
我们就是被女人养大的一代男人
We're a generation of men raised by women.
难道换个女人就能解决我们的问题了吗
I'm wondering if another woman is really the answer we need.
一周多数时间 我们就是奥兹和哈里特
Most of the week, we were Ozzie and Harriet.
奥兹和哈里特 出自美国著名情景喜剧<奥兹和哈里特的冒险> 其中两人是夫妻关系
但每周六晚上 我们就会找点儿事做
But every Saturday night, we were finding something out.
我们越发发现其实我们并不孤独
We were finding out more and more that we were not alone.
以前我总是愤怒或沮丧地回家
It used to be that when I came home angry or depressed.
我只会打扫公寓 擦亮我的斯堪的纳维亚家具
I'd just clean my condo, polish my Scandinavian furniture.
我本该在找一间新公寓
I should have been looking for a new condo.
我本该追着保险公司讨价还价
I should have been haggling with my insurance company.
我本该为那些被烧毁的高级蠢玩意儿心烦
I should have been upset about my nice flaming little shit,
但我没有
but I wasn't.
办公自动化的基本前提就是更高效地完成任务
The basic premise of cybernetting any office is make things more efficient.
周一早上 我满脑子想的都是下个星期
Monday mornings, all I can do is think about next week.
可以把图标做成菊蓝色的吗
Can I get the icon in cornflower blue?
当然可以
Absolutely.
各位 效率是第一要素
Efficiency is priority No. 1, people.
因为浪费就是偷盗
Because waste is a thief.
我已经给这位朋友展示过了 你很喜欢 对吧
I showed this already to my man here. You liked it, didn't you?
在你觉得恶心之前 能生吞多半升的鲜血
You can swallow a pint of blood before you get sick.
一切都写在大家的脸上 我和泰勒只是让其显现出来而已
It was right in everyone's face. Tyler and I just made it visible.
一切都在大家的嘴边 我和泰勒只是赋予了它一个名字
It was on the tip of everyone's tongue. Tyler and I just gave it a name.
好了 同志们 你们该回家了
Come on, people, you've gotta go home!
点唱机关了 后门锁上
Turn off the jukebox. Lock the back.
每周 泰勒都会宣读我俩定的规矩
Every week, Tyler gave the rules that he and I decided.
先生们
Gentlemen!
欢迎来到搏击俱乐部
Welcome to Fight Club.
搏击俱乐部的第一条规定是
The first rule of Fight Club is...
禁止谈论搏击俱乐部
you do not talk about Fight Club.
搏击俱乐部的第二条规定是
The second rule of Fight Club is...
禁止谈论搏击俱乐部
you do not talk about Fight Club!
第三条规定
Third rule of Fight Club:
有人喊停 瘫软 拍地认输 搏斗就得结束
someone yells stop, goes limp, taps out, the fight is over.
第四条规定 每场仅限两人
Fourth rule: only two guys to a fight.
第五条 一次一场 伙计们
Fifth rule: one fight at a time, fellas.
第六条 脱掉衬衫 脱掉鞋子
Sixth rule: no shirts, no shoes.
第七条 搏斗没有时间限制
Seventh rule: fights will go on as long as they have to.
第八条 也是最后一条规定
And the eighth and final rule...
如果这是你第一晚来搏击俱乐部
if this is your first night at Fight Club,
就必须打
you have to fight.
办公室的小弟Ricky
This kid from work, Ricky,
连你要的是蓝笔还是黑笔都记不住
couldn't remember whether you ordered pens with blue ink or black.
但他暴打当地美食广场领班的
But Ricky was a god for ten minutes
那十分钟简直犹如战神附体
when he trounced the maitre d' of a local food court.
在呐喊声中 有时你听到的只是沉闷用力的重击声
Sometimes, all you could hear were the flat, hard, packing sounds over the yelling.
或是干咳着 血腥四溅的哽咽声
Or the wet choke when someone cough breath and sprayed...
停
Stop!
在那里你比在任何地方都具有生命力
You weren't alive anywhere like you were there.
但搏击俱乐部只存在于
But Fight Club only exists in the hours between
它开始到结束的那几个小时里
when Fight Club starts and when Fight Club ends.
即便我知道有人打了很厉害的一场
Even if I could tell someone they had a good fight,
事后他还是会变回原来的样子
I wouldn't be talking to the same man.
在搏击俱乐部的你和在其余世界的你判若两人
Who you were in Fight Club is not who you were in the rest of the world.
第一次来搏击俱乐部的人
A guy came to Fight Club for the first time.
屁股像面团一样软
His ass was a wad of cookie dough.
几周后 他就如木雕一般坚挺了
After a few weeks, he was carved out of wood.
如果能和任何名人打 你要打谁
If you could fight any celebrity, who would you fight?
- 活的还是死的  - 无所谓 谁比较厉害
- Alive or dead?  - Doesn't matter. Who'd be tough?
海明威
Hemingway.
你呢
You?
夏特纳 我要打威廉·夏特纳
Shatner. I'd fight William Shatner.
威廉·夏特纳是犹太裔的加拿大籍演员
我们看事情的眼光和以前不同了
We all started seeing things differently.
不管到哪儿 我们都要评头论足一番
Everywhere we went, we were sizing things up.
我为去健身房的人感到悲哀
I felt sorry for guys packed into gyms,
想努力练到CK或是汤米·希尔费格宣传的模特身材
trying to look like how Calvin Klein or Tommy Hilfiger said they should.
均为美国时尚休闲品牌
那是男人该有的样子吗
Is that what a man looks like?
阿 自我改善只是自慰
Ah, self-improvement is masturbation.
至于自我毁灭嘛
Now, self-destruction...
借过
Excuse me.
在搏击俱乐部输赢并不重要
Fight Club wasn't about winning or losing.
也不需要语言
It wasn't about words.
各地不同方言的歇斯底里的呐喊声
The hysterical shouting was in tongues,
听着像是在五旬节教会
like at a Pentecostal Church.
五旬节会是源自美国五旬节运动的基督新教教派 特别强调说方言
- 够了吗  - 停
- Is that it?  - Stop!
打斗结束后 什么问题也不会解决
When the fight was over, nothing was solved.
但什么都不是问题了
But nothing mattered.
酷
Cool.
打过之后 我们都感觉获得了救赎
Afterwards, we all felt saved.
嘿 老兄 下个礼拜继续怎么样
Hey, man. How about next week?
还是下个月吧
How about next month?
Irvine 到你上了 那个新来的 你也上
Irvine, you're in the middle. New guy, you too.
有时候泰勒会帮我撒谎
Sometimes, Tyler spoke for me.
他从楼梯上摔下来了
He fell down some stairs.
我从楼梯上摔下来了
I fell down some stairs.
搏击俱乐部成为你剪头发还有修剪指甲的原因
Fight Club became the reason to cut your hair short or trim your fingernails.
好吧 那历史人物呢
OK. Any historical figure?
我会跟甘地打
I'd fight Gandhi.
好想法
Good answer.
- 你呢  - 林肯
- How about you?  - Lincoln.
- 林肯  - 嗯哼
- Lincoln?  - Mm-hm.
大高个儿 手长脚长  皮包骨的家伙被打成肉酱才甘心
Big guy, big reach. Skinny guys fight till they're burger.
操
Fuck!
没关系啦 蒙娜丽莎也有掉牙的那一天
Hey, even the Mona Lisa's falling apart.
喂
Hello?
你这两个月去哪儿了
Where have you been the last eight weeks?
玛拉
Marla?
- 你怎么找到我的  - 你留了转移号码呀
- How did you find me?  - You left a forwarding number.
我没在任何互助会上看到你
I haven't seen you at any support groups.
我们平分了啊 当初这么决定的 记得吗
We split 'em up. That was the idea. Remember?
是啊 但你也没去你的互助会呀
Yeah, but you haven't been going to yours.
- 你怎么知道的  - 我作弊去了
- How do you know?  - I cheated.
我找到新的了
I found a new one.
- 真的吗  - 只能男人能参加
- Really?  - It's for men only.
就像睾丸癌那种东西吗
Like the testicle thing?
听着 现在我不方便讲电话
Look, this is a bad time.
我去了负债者匿名互助会
I've been going to Debtors Anonymous.
- 你要是想看真正操蛋的人生  - 我已经找到自己的出口了
- Your wanna see some really fucked-up people...  - I've just found my way out.
我也是 我吃了好多阿普唑仑
Me too. I've got a stomach full of Xanax.
一种镇静剂
我把瓶子里剩下的都吃了 可能吃太多了
I took what was left of a bottle. It might have been too much.
想像着玛拉辛格自己躺在那破旧的公寓里
Just picture watching Marla Singer throw herself around her crummy apartment.
我不是真的要自杀 更像是个求救电话
This isn't a for-real suicide thing. It's probably one of these cry-for-help things.
她可能要搞好几个小时
This could go on for hours.
那你准备在家一直待到晚上咯
So you're staying in tonight, then?
你想慢慢听我描述死亡的感受吗
Do you wanna wait and hear me describe death?
你想听听看我的灵魂讲电话吗
Do you wanna listen and see if my spirit can use a phone?
你听过人临死前发出的哀鸣吗
Have you ever heard a death rattle before?
泰勒的门紧闭着
Tyler's door was closed.
我在这儿住了两个月 泰勒的门从没关过
I'd been here for two months and Tyler's door was never closed.
你不会相信我昨晚梦见了什么
You won't believe this dream I had last night.
我也不敢相信昨晚发生的一切
I can hardly believe anything from last night.
你 你在这里干嘛
Wha... what are you doing here?
- 什么  - 这是我家 你在我家做什么
- What?  - This is my house. What are you doing in my house?
去你妈的
Fuck you!
跟你说 你操蛋的朋友还真多啊
Oh, you've got some fucked-up friends, I'm telling you.
不过够柔韧
Limber, though.
傻缺婊子
Silly cooze.
昨晚我进屋 发现电话没挂 猜猜电话那头是谁
So I come in last night. Phone's off the hook. Guess who's on the other end?
他不说我都明白了
I already knew the story before he told it to me.
你听过人临死前发出的哀鸣吗
Have you ever heard a death rattle before?
真的会是像描述的那种嘎嘎声吗
Do you think it'll live up to its name?
还是只不过像是个死亡小毛团
Or will it just be a death hairball?
准备将灵魂咳出体外
Prepare to evacuate soul.
十
Ten...
九
Nine...
八
Eight...
茫茫人海中 为什么偏偏
Now how could Tyler, of all people,
泰勒觉得玛拉辛格要死是件坏事
think it was a bad thing that Marla Singer was about to die?
五
Five...
四
Four...
三 等下
Thr... Hang on.
你来得可真快
You got here fast.
我有给你打电话吗
Did I call you?
无所谓了
Fine.
床垫都包了层塑料 太滑了
The mattress is all sealed in slippery plastic.
别担心 它对你构不成威胁
Oh, don't worry. It's not a threat to you.
操 有人报警了
Oh, fuck! Somebody called the cops.
- 嘿 513房在哪里  - 走廊最后那间
- Hey, where's 513?  - End of the hall.
里面那个女孩儿原来是个迷人可爱的姑娘
You know, the girl who lives there used to be a charming, lovely girl.
但她对自己失去了信心
She has lost faith in herself.
- Singer小姐 我们来救你了 - 她现在就是个禽兽
- Miss Singer, let us help you!  - She's a monster!
- 你有大把的理由活下去  - 她就是个肮脏的人渣
- You have every reason to live.  - She's infectious human waste!
- Singer小姐  - 祝你们好运能救她
- Miss Singer!  - Good luck trying to save her!
要是我睡着了 我就死定了
If I fall asleep, I'm done for.
所以你得让我保持清醒
You're gonna have to keep me up...
一整晚喔
all night.
真他妈不可思议
Un-fucking-believable.
显然他轻松解决了这个问题
He was obviously able to handle it.
你懂的 你也上过她
You know what I mean. You fucked her.
不 我没有
No, I didn't.
- 从没有吗  - 没有
- Never?  - No.
- 你不是喜欢上她了吧  - 不 老天 才不是呢
- You're not into her, are you?  - No! God, not at all.
"我是Jack愤怒的胆管"
"I am Jack's raging bile duct."
- 真的吗 跟我说又没关系  - 相信我 真的
- Are you sure? You can tell me.  - Believe me, I'm sure.
拿枪对着我头 脑浆四溅墙壁 我也不承认
Put a gun to my head and paint the walls of my brains.
那就好 她就是披着羊皮的狼 离她远点儿
That's good. She's a predator posing as a house pet. Stay away from her.
从她嘴里说出的浪话 我听都没听过
The shit that came out of this woman's mouth, I had never heard!
天哪
My God.
我从小学以后就没这么被操过了
I haven't been fucked like that since grade school.
泰勒怎么会不去上她呢
How could Tyler not go for that?
前一天晚上 他还把一帧生殖器剪进"灰姑娘"里呢
Night before that, he was splicing sex organs into "Cinderella".
玛拉不需要爱人 她需要个性交社工
Marla doesn't need a lover, she needs a fucking caseworker.
她只需要个大屌 跟爱无关 我们只是打炮
She needs a wash. This isn't love, it's sport fuck.
她先是侵入我的互助会 现在又侵入我的家
She invaded my support groups and now she invaded my home.
嘿 嘿 先坐下
Hey, hey. Sit down.
听着 你不能跟她谈起我
Now, listen. I can't have you talking to her about me.
我为什么要和她说话
Why would I talk to her?
你要是跟她或任何人说了我或这屋子里的事
You say anything about me or what goes on in this house to her or to anybody...
我们就玩儿完
we're done.
- 向我发誓  - 好
- Now promise me.  - OK.
- 你发誓吗  - 对 我发誓
- You promise?  - Yeah, I promise.
- 发誓了吗  - 我刚说了 我发誓 搞什么
- Promise?  - I just said, I promise! What...
你发了三遍誓
That's three times you promised.
要是当时我浪费几分钟 去玛拉辛格家眼看着等她死
If only I had wasted a couple of minutes and gone to watch Marla Singer die,
就不会有这些破事儿了
none of this would've happened.
用力 对 使劲 使劲 爽
Harder, yes! Oh, harder, harder, yeah!
我可以搬到另一个房间
I could have moved to another room.
在三楼可能就听不到他们的声音了
On the third floor where I might not have heard them.
但我没搬
But I didn't.
你在干嘛
What are you doing?
准备上床睡觉啊
Just going to bed.
要不要帮我操完她
You wanna finish her off?
- 不 不了 谢谢  - 我找到根烟
- No. No, thank you.  - I found a cigarette.
- 你在跟谁说话  - 闭嘴
- Who were you talking to?  - Shut up.
我成了世界上平静的小小中心
I became the calm little center of the world.
我是禅宗大师
I was the Zen master.
工蜂可以离开
雄蜂亦可飞走
蜂后才是它们的奴隶
我写了些三行俳句诗
I wrote little haiku poems.
我把它电邮给每个人
I emailed them to everyone.
那是你的血吗
Is that your blood?
有些是
Some of it, yeah.
你不能在这儿抽烟
You can't smoke in here.
你现在就回家休息吧 下周一穿件干净衣服来上班
Take the rest of the day off. Come back Monday with some clean clothes.
打起精神来
Get yourself together.
我明白每个人面对我时充满敌意的面庞
I got right in everyone's hostile little face.
"对 这是打架留下的瘀青"
"Yes, these are bruises from fighting."
"对 我乐意 我顿悟人生了"
"Yes, I'm comfortable with that. I am enlightened."
你放弃公寓生活
You give up the condo life,
放弃你所有那些烧毁的身外之物
give up all your flaming worldly possessions,
搬进一个重污染区里的破烂房子
go live in a dilapidated house in a toxic-waste part of town,
回到家还得听这个
...and you have to come home to this.
喂
Hello?
我是纵火科的Stern警探
Yes, this is Detective Stern with the Arson Unit.
关于你之前那所公寓的火灾 我们有了新线索
We have new information about the incident at your former condo.
- 是什么  - 不知道你注意到了没有
- Yes?  - I don't know if you're aware,
好像有人在你的门锁里喷了氟里昂
but it seems someone sprayed Freon into your front-door lock.
氟利昂 一种制冷剂
然后用凿子敲碎了锁芯
Then tapped it with a chisel to shatter the cylinder.
不 我完全不知道
No, I wasn't aware of that at all.
"我是Jack的冷汗"
"I am Jack's cold sweat."
- 你不觉得奇怪吗  - 呃 是啊 先生 非常奇怪
- Does this sound strange to you?  - Uh, yes, sir, strange. Very strange.
- 炸药  - 什么炸药
- The dynamite...  - Dynamite?
在现场留下了草酸铵钾氯化钾的残留物
...left a residue of ammonium oxalate potassium perchloride.
- 知道这表明什么吗  - 不知道 表明什么
- Do you know what this means?  - No. What does it mean?
表明那是自制的炸药
It means it was home-made.
抱歉 这着实让我吃了一惊 先生
I'm sorry. This is just coming as quite a shock to me, sir.
放置这些自制炸药的人
You see, whoever set this dynamite
可能在爆炸前几天就熄灭了你灶上的常燃小火
could have blown out your pilot light days before the explosion.
- 天然气泄漏只是导火索而已  - 谁会做这种事
- The gas was just a detonator.  - Who would go and do such a thing?
- 这我就要问你了  - 告诉他啊
- I'll ask the questions.  - Tell him.
告诉他谁是烧毁了我的财物但重建了我认知的解救者
Tell him the liberator who destroyed my property realigned my perceptions.
你好 你还在听吗
Excuse me. Are you there?
我 我在听 只是很难搞清楚是怎么回事儿
I... I am listening. It's... it's a little hard to know what to make of all this.
你最近有什么能搞到
Have you recently made enemies of anyone
这种自制炸药的仇人吗
who might have access to home-made dynamite?
仇人
Enemies?
他拒绝基础文明 特别是物质财产的重要性
who reject the basic civilization, especially the improtance of material possessions.
- 孩子 这事很严重  - 是 我知道很严重
- Son, this is serious.  - Yes, I know it's serious.
- 我说真的  - 是的 非常严重
- I mean that.  - Yes, it's very serious.
听着 没人比我更重视这件事 那间公寓就是我的命 知道吗
Look, nobody takes this more seriously than me. That condo was my life, OK?
里面的每件家具都是我的宝贝
I loved every stick of furniture in that place.
被毁掉的不只是那一堆东西
That was not just a bunch of stuff that got destroyed.
而是我
It was me!
真要好好感谢大学教育
I'd like to thank the Academy.
你现在不方便说话吗
Is this not a good time for you?
直接告诉他全他妈是你干的
Just tell him you fucking did it!
告诉他你把公寓炸飞了 他就想听这个
Tell him you blew it all up! That's what he wants to hear.
- 你还在听吗  - 等等 你是说我有嫌疑吗
- Are you still there?  - Wait. Are you saying that I'm a suspect?
不 不 我可能需要好好跟你谈谈
No. No. I may need to talk to you for this.
如果你要出城的话 记得告诉我
How about you just let me know if you're gonna leave town?
- 好吗  - 好
- OK?  - OK.
除了做床上运动 泰勒和玛拉从不在同一房间出现
Except for their humping, Tyler and Marla were never in the same room.
我爸妈也曾这样好多年
My parents pulled this exact same act for years.
保险套就是我们这代人的水晶鞋
The condom is the glass slipper of our generation.
遇到陌生人 就套上一个
You slip one on when you meet a stranger.
跳一整晚舞 然后就丢掉
You dance all night, then you throw it away.
我是说保险套 不是陌生人
The condom, I mean. Not the stranger.
什么
What?
我在二手店花一美元买的这条裙子
I got this dress at a thrift store for $1.
真是物有所值
It was worth every penny.
这是伴娘礼服
It's a bridesmaid's dress.
某人只钟爱了它一天
Someone loved it intensely for one day,
然后就扔了
then tossed it.
就像颗圣诞树
Like a Christmas tree.
如此特别
So special.
然后 嘭一声
Then... bam!
就被丢在路边
It's on the side of the road.
树上的金属亮片还挂着呢
Tinsel still clinging to it.
就像性犯罪的受害者 内裤反穿
Like a sex-crime victim, underwear inside out,
还被绝缘胶带绑着
bound with electrical tape.
那这件衣服的确适合你
Well, then, it suits you.
想穿我可以借你
You can borrow it sometime.
赶走她
Get rid of her.
- 什么 嘿 你自己赶她走  - 别提到我
- What? Hey, you get rid of her!  - Don't mention me.
我又回到了六岁 给爸妈当传话筒
I am six years old again, passing messages between parents.
- 我觉得你真的该走了  - 别担心 我这就走
- You know, I really think it's time you got out of here.  - Don't worry, I'm leaving.
不是我们不喜欢你的小造访
Not that we don't love your little visits.
你就是个疯子 我是真心赶不上你的节奏
You know, you are such a nutcase. I can't even begin to keep up.
该走咯
Gotta get off...
Cryptic Tales的歌曲<Valley Of The Dolls Ii>
谢谢 再见
Thanks. Bye.
该下来这个旋转木马咯
Gotta get off of this merry-go-round...
该走了 得走了 该走
Gonna get, need to get, gotta get...
真是俩小孩
You kids!
为什么还要在她身上浪费时间
Why do you still waste time with her?
因为玛拉 至少她有努力彻底堕落
I'll say this about Marla. At least she's trying to hit bottom.
怎么 我不是吗
What, and I'm not?
屁股上插了根毛儿你也变不成鸡
Sticking feathers up your butt does not make you a chicken.
我们今晚要干什么
What are we doing tonight?
今晚
Tonight...
我们做肥皂
we make soap.
- 是嘛  - 要做肥皂 我们得先提炼脂肪
- Really?  - To make soap, first we render fat.
盐分的比例要刚刚好
The salt balance has to be just right,
所以做肥皂最好的脂肪就是人的脂肪
so the best fat for making soap comes from humans.
- 等等 这是哪里  - 抽脂诊所
- Wait. What is this place?  - A liposuction clinic.
啊哈 找到宝
Aha! Pay dirt!
世上最油滑的脂肪 脂肪之王
Richest, creamiest fat in the world. Fat of the land!
别
No!
不要拉
Don't pull it.
- 老天  - 再拿一包
- Oh, God! - Give another one.
提炼脂肪时 动物脂肪就会浮到表面
As the fat renders, the tallows float to the surface.
就像童子军时学的那样
Like in Boy Scouts.
- 很难想象你当童子军是什么模样  - 继续搅
- It's hard to imagine you as a Boy Scout.  - Keep stirring.
动物脂冻硬后 提取出一层甘油
Once the tallow hardens, you skim off a layer of glycerin.
加上硝酸 就有了硝化甘油
If you add nitric acid, you've got nitroglycerin.
再加硝酸钠和一点儿锯屑 就成了炸药
If you then add sodium nitrate and a dash of sawdust, you've got dynamite.
所以只要肥皂够多 想炸飞什么都行
Yeah, with enough soap, one could blow up just about anything.
泰勒满脑子都是有用的知识
Tyler was full of useful information.
古人发现在河流的某一处
Now, ancient peoples found clothes got cleaner
衣服洗得特别干净
when washed at a certain point in the river.
- 知道为什么吗  - 不知道
- You know why?  - No.
曾有人牺牲在河边的山上
Humans sacrifices were once made on the hills above this river.
尸体被燃烧后 水渗入了骨灰中 产生了碱
Bodies burned, water seeped through the ashes to create lye.
这就是碱 关键成分
This is lye. The crucial ingredient.
一旦它与烧熔的尸体脂肪混合
Once it mixed with the melted fat bodies,
就变成白花花的肥皂水慢慢流入河中
then white soapy discharge crept into the river.
我能看看你的手吗
May I see your hand, please?
你这是做什么
What is this?
这叫做化学灼伤
This is chemical burn.
比你经历的任何烧伤都要痛
It'll hurt more than you've ever been burned
- 而且会留下疤痕  - 你做什么
- and it will leave a scar.  - What are you doing?
老天 冥想对癌症有用 对这个也应该有用
God! Meditation worked for cancer, it could work for this.
- 好好感受这疼痛 不要逃避  - 不 不 天哪
- Stay with the pain! Don't shut this out.  - No! No! Oh, God!
看看你的手 最早的肥皂都是由英雄的灰烬而来
Look at your hand! The first soap was made from ashes of heroes,
就像第一只被射上太空的猴子
like the first monkey shot into space.
没有痛苦 没有牺牲 我们会一无所有
Without pain, without sacrifice, we would have nothing.
我努力不去想"灼烧"和"血肉"这些词
I tried not to think of the words "Searing" or "Flesh".
停下 这是你的痛苦 这是你正在灼烧的手 你没法逃避的
Stop it! This is your pain, this is your burning hand. It's right here.
我要到我的洞里去 我要找我的灵魂动物
I'm going to my cave. I'm going to find my power animal.
别用死人那套面对这些 专注点儿
No! Don't deal with this the way those dead people do! Come on!
- 我懂你意思了  - 不
- I get the point!  - No!
你正在感受的是初始启蒙阶段
What you're feeling is premature enlightenment.
这是你人生最棒的时刻 老兄 而你却在开小差
It's the greatest moment of your life, man, and you're off somewhere missing it!
我没有
I am not...
闭嘴 我们的父亲就是我们心目中上帝的化身
Shut up! Our fathers were our models for God.
连父亲都抛弃了我们 你觉得上帝呢
If our fathers bailed, what does that tell you about God?
不 我不
No, I don't...
听我说
Listen to me.
你必须得考虑到也许上帝并不喜欢你
You have to consider the possibility that God does not like you.
他压根儿不想要你 十有八九 他甚至憎恶你
He never wanted you. In all probability, he hates you.
- 现在发生的还不是最惨的事  - 还不是吗
- This is not the worst thing that can happen. - It isn't?
我们不需要他
We don't need him!
- 不需要 我同意 我懂了   - 去他妈的天谴 去他妈的救赎
- We don't, I agree! I get it... - Fuck damnation, and fuck redemption.
我们是上帝不想要的孩子 那就是吧
We are God's unwanted children? So be it!
- 我要水  - 听着 你可以用水让伤情更糟 或者
- I'm getting water!  - Listen, you can use water and make it worse or...
看着我
Look at me!
你可以用醋来中和烧伤
Or you can use vinegar to neutralize the burn.
求你给我醋吧 求你了
Please let me have it, please!
首先 你必须要放弃
First, you have to give up.
首先 你必须要明白 不是惧怕 总有一天你会死
First, you have to know, not fear, know that someday, you're gonna die.
你不知道这有多疼
You don't know how this feels!
只有失去一切 我们才能随心所欲去做任何事
It's only after we've lost everything that we're free to do anything.
好了
OK.
恭喜你 你离彻底堕落又近了一步
Congratulations. You're one step closer to hitting the bottom.
泰勒以每块20美元的价格把肥皂卖给百货公司
Tyler sold his soap to department stores at $20 a bar.
天知道他们卖多少钱
God knows what they charged.
这是最好的肥皂
This is the best soap.
多谢你 苏珊
Well, thank you, Susan.
干得漂亮
It was beautiful.
我们把富婆屁股上的脂肪又回卖给她们
We were selling rich women their own fat asses back to them.
他系了黄色领带
He was wearing his yellow tie.
我上班都已经不系领带了
I didn't even wear a tie to work anymore.
"搏击俱乐部的第一条规定是禁止谈论搏击俱乐部"
"The first rule of Fight Club is you don't talk about Fight Club"?
我又开始半睡半醒了 我肯定是把那张纸忘在复印机上了
I'm half-asleep again. I must have left it in the copy machine.
"搏击俱乐部的第二条规定" 这是你的吗
"The second rule of Fight Club..." Is this yours?
啊
Huh?
假设你是我 做个管理决定
Pretend you're me. Make a managerial decision.
你发现了这个 你会怎么做
You find this. What would you do?
我告诉你
Well, I gotta tell you,
我会非常 非常小心你在谈话的这个人
I'd be very, very careful who you talk to about that.
因为写下了这个的人是个危险人物
Because the person who wrote that is dangerous.
这个穿着整齐职业装的疯子可能会突然失控
And this button-down, Oxford-cloth psycho might just snap
拿着一把阿玛莱特AR10
and then stalk from office to office
半自动卡宾枪暴走过一间一间办公室
with an Armalite AR10 carbine gas-powered semiautomatic weapon,
用一梭梭子弹把同事打成马蜂窝
pumping round after round into colleagues and co-workers.
他可能是你认识多年的人
This might be someone you've known for years.
跟你非常非常亲近的人
Someone very, very close to you.
泰勒的话从我嘴里冒出来
Tyler's words coming out of my mouth.
我以前是多和善一人啊
And I used to be such a nice guy.
要不就别每捡到个垃圾就来找我
Or maybe you shouldn't bring me every piece of trash you happen to pick up.
- 合规责任部门  - 我的奶头要烂掉了
- Compliance and Liability.  - My tit's gonna rot off.
能请你出去吗 我要接个电话
Will you excuse me? I need to take this.
你说什么呢
What are you talking about?
我需要你帮我检查下胸部有没有肿块
I need you to check and see if there's a lump in my breast.
- 去医院啊  - 我可没钱浪费在医生身上
- Go to a hospital.  - I can't afford to throw money on a doctor.
我不知道 玛拉
I don't know about this, Marla.
求你了
Please?
她没有找泰勒 我在她眼里就是中性的
She didn't call Tyler. I'm neutral in her book.
不错嘛 给Haniver和Raines夫人送餐
That's nice. Taking food to... Mrs. Haniver and Mrs. Raines.
她们在哪儿呢
Where are they, exactly?
不幸的是 她们都死了 而我还活着而且很穷 要吃吗
Tragically, they're dead. I'm alive and I'm in poverty. Want any?
- 不 不用  - 我给你拿了一份
- No, no.  - I got one for you.
谢谢你的好意
Thanks for the thought.
你手怎么了
What happened to your hand?
没什么
Oh, nothing.
- 是这里吗  - 嗯
- Right there?  - Mm.
感觉到什么吗
Feel anything?
没有
No.
再确认一下
Well, make sure.
好了 我 我很确定
OK, I... I'm pretty sure.
你真的什么都没感觉到
You feel nothing?
没 没有
No, nothing.
那真是松了一口气 谢了
Well, that's a relief. Thank you.
- 呃 不谢  - 我希望能还你人情
- Uh... No problem.  - I wish I could return the favor.
我家里没什么得过乳癌的男人
There's not a lot of breast cancer men in my family.
- 我可以检查你的前列腺  - 我觉得我挺好
- I could check your prostate.  - I think I'm OK.
那还是谢谢了
Well, thanks, anyway.
- 完事儿了吗  - 对 没事儿了
- Are we done?  - Yeah, we're done.
回头 见
See you... around.
Cornelius
Cornelius?
Cornelius!
是我啊 Bob
It's me! Bob!
嘿 Bob
Hey, Bob.
- 我们都以为你已经死了呢  - 没 没 我还活着呢
- We all thought you were dead.  - No, no. Still here.
你好吗 Bob
How are you, Bob?
我这辈子都没这么好过
Better than I've ever been in my whole life.
是嘛 还在参加"一起继续做男人"互助会吗
Really? Still Remaining Men Together?
不 不 我找到了更好的寄托
No, no. I got something so much better now.
真的吗 是什么
Really, what is it?
那个 第一条规定是我不能谈论它
Well.. the first rule is, I'm not supposed to talk about it.
第二条规定是
And the second rule is...
我不能谈论它
I'm not supposed to talk about it.
- 第三条规定是  - Bob Bob 我也是其中一员
- And the third rule is...  - Bob, Bob. I'm a member.
看我的脸 Bob
Look at my face, Bob.
这真是太他妈 太他妈棒了
That's fucking... fucking great.
- 我从没在那儿见过你啊  - 我周二跟周四去
- I've never seen you there.  - I go Tuesdays and Thursdays.
- 我周六去  - 恭喜啊
- I go Saturday.  - Congratulations.
对 嘿 恭喜我们两个吧
Yeah, hey, to both of us, right?
你听说过发起这个的人吗
Have you heard about the guy that invented this thing?
- 对 其实我  - 我听了好多传说  - 是吗
- Well, yeah, actually I...  - I hear all kinds of things. - Yeah?
据说 他是在精神病院出生的
Supposedly, he was born in a mental institution,
他每天晚上只睡一个小时
and he sleeps only one hour a night.
- 他是个伟人  - 哇
- He's a great man.  - Oh...
你知道泰勒·德顿吗
Do you know about Tyler Durden?
撂倒他
Take him down!
房身健界世
我没伤到你吧
I didn't hurt you, did I?
说实话 你伤到了
Actually, you did.
谢谢你跟我打了一场 谢谢 谢谢 谢谢
Thank you for this. Thank you, thank you, thank you.
搏击俱乐部
Fight Club.
Bob Bob
Bob, Bob...
这是我和泰勒的礼物
This was mine and Tyler's gift.
我们给世人的礼物
Our gift to the world.
我环顾四周 看到很多新面孔
I look around, I look around, I see a lot of new faces.
闭嘴
Shut up!
这意味着很多人没有遵守搏击俱乐部的前两条规定
Which means a lot of people breaking the first two rules of Fight Club.
我在搏击俱乐部里看到了最强悍最聪明的人
I see in Fight Club the strongest and smartest men who've ever lived.
我看到了各种潜能 也看到它们被浪费
I see all this potential. And I see it squandered.
该死的 整整一代人都在给人加油
Goddamn it, an entire generation pumping gas.
给人端盘子
Waiting tables.
做白领奴隶
Slaves with white collars.
广告诱导我们追求豪车华服
Advertising has us chasing cars and clothes.
干我们讨厌的工作 只为能买我们不需要的破烂儿
Working jobs we hate so we can buy shit we don't need.
我们是被历史遗忘的一代 伙计们
We're the middle children of history, men.
没有目标 没有地位
No purpose or place.
我们没有世界大战
We have no Great War.
没有经济大萧条
No Great Depression.
我们的大战是心灵之战
Our great war is a spiritual war.
我们的大萧条是我们的生活
Our great depression is our lives.
我们从小看电视 相信有一天
We've all been raised on television to believe that one day
我们都能成为百万富翁 电影巨星 或是摇滚明星
we'd be millionaires and movie gods and rock stars.
但我们不会
But we won't.
我们慢慢认识到这个事实
We're slowly learning that fact.
所以我们非常非常气愤
And we're very, very pissed off.
没错
Yeah!
搏击俱乐部第一条规定是 禁止谈论
First rule of Fight Club is, do not talk about...
你是谁
Who are you?
- 我是谁  - 对
- Who am I?  - Yeah.
前面有块牌子写着"卢的酒馆"
There's a sign on the front that says Lou's Tavern.
我他妈就是卢 你他妈又是谁
I'm fucking Lou. Who the fuck are you?
泰勒·德顿
Tyler Durden.
谁允许你们这帮混蛋用我的地方了
Who told you motherfuckers you could use my place?
我们跟Irvine讲好了的
We have a deal worked out with Irvine.
Irvine Irvine断了根锁骨在家躺着呢
Irvine? Irvine's at home with a broken collarbone.
这地方不归他 归我
He don't own this place. I do.
- 他从中得了多少钱  - 一毛没有
- How much money's he getting for this?  - There is no money.
- 真的吗  - 免费对我们开放
- Really?  - Free to all.
- 还真不可思议啊  - 的确如此
- Ain't that something.  - It is, actually.
听着 你个蠢货
Look, stupid fuck!
我要所有人立马给我滚出去
I want everybody out of here right now.
嘿 你也该加入我们俱乐部
Hey! You should join our club.
- 你没听到我刚说什么吗  - 你跟你的朋友都该加入
- Did you hear what I just said?  - You and your friend.
你现在听到了吗
You hear me now?
不 我没怎么听到 卢
No, I didn't quite catch that, Lou.
还是没听到
Still not getting it.
好了 好了 我听到了
OK, OK, I got it.
我听到了 听到了 操 我又给忘了
I got it, I got it. Shit, I lost it.
退后 都给我退后
Back! All of you!
所有人退后
Everybody back!
啊 卢
Ah, Lou!
拜托 老兄 我们真的很喜欢这地方
Come on, man! We really like this place.
没错 卢 发泄出来吧
That's right, Lou. Get it out.
- 他妈的闭嘴  - 噢 爽
- Shut the fuck up.  - Oh, yeah!
这他妈很搞笑吗
Is that fucking funny?
这家伙就他妈是个疯子
Fucking guy's a loony, I'm telling you.
难以置信
Unbelievable.
- 你不知道我都经历过什么 卢  - 天哪
- You don't know where I've been, Lou.  - Oh, my God!
你不知道我都经历过什么
You don't know where I've been!
让我们继续用这里吧 卢 求你了 卢
Please let us keep it, Lou! Please, Lou!
他妈想用就用吧 上帝啊
Fucking use the basement! Christ!
你得向我保证 卢 向我保证
I want your word, Lou! I want your word!
以我妈的名义保证
On my mother's eyes.
谢了 卢
Thanks, Lou.
也谢谢你 大个子
You too, big guy.
我们下周见了
We'll see you next week.
这周 你们每个人都有个作业
This week, each one of you has a homework assignment.
你们要出去 找个完全不认识的人打一架
You're gonna go out. You're gonna start a fight with a total stranger.
你们得主动找人打
You're gonna start a fight,
但你们必须打输
and you're gonna lose.
眼光不错喔 先生
Excellent choice, sir.
嘿 看着点儿 混蛋 干什么呢
Hey! Watch out, jackass! Come on!
这作业可不像听起来那么简单
Now, this is not as easy as it sounds.
什 狗娘养的
What... son of a bitch!
大多数人 正常人 都会想尽办法避免打架
Most people, normal people, do just about anything to avoid a fight.
不好意思
Excuse me!
刚才你的水管喷到我了
You sprayed me with your hose.
没必要这么做
That's not necessary.
Jay 快打电话报警
Jay! Go call 911!
把水管放下
Put the hose down.
住手 住手
Stop it! Stop it!
对不起
Sorry.
我们得谈谈
We need to talk.
行啊
Ok.
从哪儿说起呢
Where to begin?
你的经常性旷工
With your constant absenteeism?
还是你见不得人的仪容
With your unpresentable appearance?
你得准备好接受审查了
You're up for review.
"我是Jack的完全不出所料"
"I am Jack's complete lack of surprise."
- 什么  - 让我们假设一下
- What?  - Let's pretend.
如果你是交通部的人
You're the Department of Transportation, OK?
有人告诉你
Someone informs you that
这家公司汽车安装的前座支架
this company installs front-seat mounting brackets
根本没通过撞车试验
that never pass collision tests,
开过1600公里 刹车片就会失灵
brake linings that fail after 1,000 miles,
还有喷油器就会爆炸把人活活烧死
and fuel injectors that explode and burn people alive.
你会怎么做
What then?
- 你是在威胁我吗  - 不
- Are you threatening me?  - No...
他妈的滚出去 你被炒了
Get the fuck out of here. You're fired!
我有个更好的解决办法
I have a better solution.
你把我转成带薪外聘顾问
You keep me on the payroll as an outside consultant,
作为交换
and in exchange for my salary,
我的工作就是永远不把我知道的这些事说出去
my job will be never to tell people these things that I know.
我甚至不用来上班 我可以在家做好这份工作
I don't even have to come into the office. I can do this job from home.
你 你他妈以为自己是谁 你个疯子
Who... who the fuck do you think you are, you crazy little shit?
- 保安  - "我是Jack偷笑的报复"
- Security!  - "I am Jack's smirking revenge."
你这是在干什么
What the hell are you doing?
好疼啊
That hurt.
你为什么要打我
Why would you do that?
天哪 不要 求求你住手
Oh, my God! No! Please stop!
你要做什么
What are you doing?
老天 不 求你了 不要
Oh, God, no! Please! No!
莫名地 我想起了我和Tlyer打的第一架
For some reason, I thought of my first fight, with Tyler.
不要
No!
在所有这家伙认为理所当然的东西背后
Under and behind and inside everything this man took for granted,
地区经理 联邦汽车公司
地区经理
已经滋生了可怕的东西
something horrible had been growing.
听着 只要像我要求的那样付我薪水就行了
Look. Just give me the paychecks, like I asked,
你就再也不会看到我了
and you won't ever see me again.
就在那时 在我俩相处过程中最赞的那一刻
And right then, at our most excellent moment together...
谢天谢地 求你别再打我了 求你了
Thank God! Please don't hit me again. Please...
电话 电脑 传真机
Telephone, computer, fax machine,
52张周薪支票 还有48张航班通票
52 weekly paychecks and 48 airline flight coupons.
我们现在有"企业赞助"了
We now had corporate sponsorship.
这样我和泰勒每晚都能去搏击俱乐部了
This is how Tyler and I were able to have Fight Club every night of the week.
现在 只有正在打架的两人才是搏击俱乐部的中心
Now, nobody was the center of Fight Club except the two men fighting.
领头人则穿梭在人群里 时现在黑暗中
The leader walked through the crowd, out in the darkness.
泰勒因为往汤里撒尿
Tyler was now involved in a lawsuit with the Pressman Hotel
正被普莱斯曼酒店起诉
over the urine content of their soup.
"我是Jack荒废的人生"
"I am Jack's wasted life."
太棒了 太棒了
Yeah! Yeah!
谢谢你 长官
Thank you, sir.
泰勒想出了新的作业
Tyler dreamed up new homework assignments.
他把作业封在信封里发给大家
He handed them out in sealed envelopes.
你知道吗
你可以用废弃的机油给草坪施肥
环保局
- 你知道特拉华市也有搏击俱乐部了吗  - 对 听说了
- Do you know there's a Fight Club in Delaware City?  - Yeah, I heard.
错误道
禁止入内
彭斯格罗夫也有了一个
There's one in Penns Grove too.
Bob甚至在纽卡斯尔也发现一个
Bob even found one up in New Castle.
是啊 那是你成立的吗
Yeah, did you start that one?
- 不是 我还以为是你呢  - 不是
- No, I thought you did.  - No.
警方查获了鸟粪投射器
表演艺术家被"性骚扰"
本地商场突然断电
喷泉被污染
失踪猴子惨遭剃毛
- 等一下  - 嘿 我们要干嘛
- Stop for a second.  - Hey, what are we doing?
- 转过去  - 我们是要干嘛
- Turn around.  - What are we doing?
- 做作业  - 什么作业
- Homework assignment.  - What kind of homework assignment?
人类牺牲
Human sacrifice.
嘿 那是枪吗 拜托 告诉我那不是枪
Hey, is that a gun? Please! Please tell me that's not a gun.
- 是枪  - 你到底要做什么  - 到后面等我
- It's a gun.  - What are you doing?  - Meet me in the back.
- 不 不 嘿 别胡来  - 到后面等我
- No. No. Hey, don't fuck around!  - Meet me in the back.
在漫长时间轴上的某一点
On a long enough time line,
每个人的存活率都会降为零
the survival rate for everyone drops to zero.
- 住手 你要干嘛 别这样  - 手放到背后
- Stop. What are you doing? Come on! - Hands behind your back.
- 天哪  - 把你钱包给我
- God!  - Give me your wallet.
Raymond K. Hessel 班宁街东南1320号A室
Raymond K. Hessel. 1320 SE Banning, Apartment A.
是狭小局促的地下室吧 Raymond
Small, cramped basement apartment, Raymond?
你怎么知道的
How did you know?
因为破地下室的地址只给字母不给号码
'Cause they give shitty basement apartments letters instead of numbers.
Raymond
Raymond!
你就要死了
You're going to die.
不要
No!
这是你爸妈吗
Is that your mom and dad?
老爸老妈 你们得打电话给体贴的牙医
Mom and Dad, you're gonna have to call up kindly Dr. So-And-So.
拿儿子的牙科记录了 想知道为什么吗
Pick up your dental records. You wanna know why?
- 因为我会拿枪轰掉你整张脸  - 不要
- 'Cause there gonna be nothing left of your face.  - No!
- 拜托 别这样  - 一张过期的社区大学学生证
- Oh, come on! Come on!  - An expired community college student ID.
你学的什么 Raymond
What did you study, Raymond?
- 就 就一些东西  - 东西
- S... stuff.  - Stuff?
期中考试难吗
Were the midterms hard?
- 我问你学的什么  - 生物 主要是
- I asked you what you studied!  - Biology, mostly.
- 为什么  - 我不知道
- Why?  - I don't know.
你以前想干什么 Raymond K. Hessel
What did you wanna be, Raymond K. Hessel?
我的问题是 Raymond 你以前想干的是什么
The question, Raymond, was what did you want to be?
快回答他 Raymond 老天
Answer him, Raymond! Jesus!
- 兽医 兽医  - 动物啊
- Veterinarian. Veterinarian.  - Animals.
- 对 动物 之类的  - 之类的 行 我知道了
- Yeah. Animals... stuff.  - Stuff. Yeah, I got that.
- 也就是说你还有一堆东西要学  - 根本学不完
- That means you need more schooling.  - Too much school.
- 那你是情愿死掉吗  - 不 求你
- Would you rather be dead?  - No, please...
你情愿死在这里 跪在一间便利店后面
You'd rather die here, on your knees, in the back of a convenience store?
不 不要 求你了 不要
No. No. Please, no.
我拿走你的驾照了
I'm keeping your license.
我会去查你的 我知道你住哪儿
Gonna check in on you. I know where you live.
如果接下来的一个半月你没在努力成为一个兽医
If you're not on your way to become a veterinarian in six weeks,
你就死定了
you will be dead.
跑回家去吧
Now run on home.
跑啊 阿甘 跑啊
Run, Forrest, run!
《阿甘正传》中的著名台词
我感觉不舒服
I feel ill.
- 想想他是什么感觉  - 拜托 这有什么好玩的
- Imagine how he feels.  - Come on, this isn't funny!
一点儿都不好玩 这他妈有什么意义
That wasn't funny. What the fuck was the point of that?
明天会是Raymond K. Hessel一生中最美好的一天
Tomorrow will be the most beautiful day of Raymond K. Hessel's life.
他的早餐会比我们吃过的任何一餐都要美味
His breakfast will taste better than any meal you and I have ever tasted.
你不得不佩服他
You had to give it to him.
走了
Come on.
他早有计划
He had a plan.
而且泰勒的理念越来越有道理了
And it started to make sense in a Tyler sort of way.
不要惧怕 不要分心
No fear. No distractions.
把一切无关紧要之事都抛之脑后的能力
The ability to let that which does not matter truly slide.
工作不能代表你
You are not your job.
银行存款不能代表你
You're not how much money you have in the bank.
你开的车也不能代表你
You're not the car you drive.
钱包里的东西不能代表你
You're not the contents of your wallet.
你的卡其裤也他妈不能代表你
You're not your fucking khakis.
你就是迎合这世界的活生生一坨屎
You are the all-singing, all-dancing crap of the world.
我马上就走
I'll be out of your way in a sec.
你没必要离开啦
You don't have to go.
随便吧
Whatever.
不 我是说
No, I mean...
没关系了
It's OK.
你还参加那些互助会吗
Are you still going to groups?
是啊
Yeah.
Chloe死了
Chloe's dead.
哇 Chloe
Wow. Chloe.
什么时候的事
When did that happen?
你在乎吗
Do you care?
不知道 我有一阵子没想到她了
I dunno. I haven't thought about it in a while.
是啊
Yeah, well...
对她来说死了也算是明智之举
It was the smart move on her part.
听着 呃
Listen, um...
你 你这样做有什么好处吗
Wha... what are you getting out of all this?
什么
What?
我是说 这一切 为什么你一直
I mean, all this. Why do you keep...
这么做会让你开心吗
Is this making you happy?
有时候会啊
Yeah, well, sometimes.
我 我不懂 我不明白
Well... I don't know. I don't understand.
为 为什么弱者总是要依附于强者
Why... why does a weaker person need to latch on to a strong person?
这 这算什么
What... what is that?
你又从中得到了什么
What do you get out of it?
不 那 那根本是两码事
No. That's... that's not the same thing at all.
我俩的情况完全不同 我们
It's totally different with us. We...
"我们"
"Us"?
- 什么叫"我们"  - 抱歉 你听到了吗
- What do you mean by "us"?  - I'm sorry. Do you hear this?
- 听到什么  - 你没听到那么吵的噪音吗 等我一下
- Hear what?  - You are not hearing all that noise? Just hold on a second.
不 等等
No, wait!
你刚才到底在说什么 别转换话题 我要和你好好谈谈
Wha... what were you saying? Don't change the subject! I want to talk about this.
- 你们没在说我吧  - 没有
- You're not talking about me, are you?  - No.
- 什么  - 那天你到我家帮我检查胸部 那算怎么回事
- What?  - That day came over to my place play doctor. What was going on there?
- 你们在聊什么呢  - 没 没什么
- What are you talking about?  - Nothing. Nothing.
- 我可不这么认为  - 拜托 你到底想怎样
- I don't think so.  - Come on. What do you want?
- 看着我  - 不 干嘛  - 看着我
- Look at me.  - No. What?  - Look at me.
- 你的手怎么了  - 没什么 不用大惊小怪
- What is that?  - It's nothing. Don't worry about it.
- 天哪 这是谁干的  - 一个人
- My God. Who did this?  - A person.
男的还是女的
Guy or girl?
- 你管得着男的还是女的  - 我问问又怎么了
- What do you care, if it's guy or girl?  - What do you care if I ask?
- 不关你的事 别烦我  - 你不敢说
- It's none of your business. Leave me alone.  - You're afraid to say.
- 我不是不敢说 放开我  - 不 告诉我
- I am not afraid to say. Let me go.  - No! Talk to me.
- 放开我  - 不行  - 别烦我
- Let go of me.  - No!  - Leave me alone!
- 这次谈话  - 这次谈话
- This conversation...  - This conversation...
- 结束了  - 结束了
- ... is over.  - ... is over.
我就是没办法讨好你 是吧
I just can't win with you, can I?
嘿 老这样就招人烦了吧
Hey, this is getting a little old!
这 这些都是什么
What... what is all this?
你觉得呢
What do you think?
嘿 我们要这些上下铺干什么
Hey, why... why do we need bunk beds?
嘿
Hey!
太年轻了 抱歉
Too young. Sorry.
那是干什么的
What's all that?
对了 如果申请人太年轻 就告诉他太年轻
Right, if the applicant is too young, tell him he's too young.
老的说太老 肥的说太肥
Old, too old. Fat, too fat.
什么申请人
Applicant?
要是申请人还是在外面等了三天
If the applicant then waits for three days
没吃没住没人鼓励的话
without food or shelter or encouragement,
他才能进来开始训练
he may then enter and begin training.
训 训练什么
Tra... training for what?
你以为这是儿戏吗
You think this is a game?
你太嫩了不可能接受训练 没戏
You're too young to train here, end of story.
别浪费我们的时间 快给我滚
Quit wasting our time. Get the fuck out of here.
坏消息 朋友
Bad news, friend.
不可能的
It's not gonna happen.
如果你误会了那真对不起
Sorry if there was a misunderstanding.
这又不是世界末日 就 离开吧
It's not the end of the world. Just... go away.
走吧
Go.
你这是私闯民宅 再不走我就报警了
You're trespassing and I will have to call the police.
还敢盯着我
Don't you look at me!
你以为你能进来吗
You think you're gonna get in this house?
你他妈这辈子都别想进来
You're never getting in this fucking house!
永远不可能 滚出我的门廊 快滚开
Never. Now get the fuck off my porch. Get off my porch!
早晚我们都会成为泰勒期望的人
Sooner or later, we all became what Tyler wanted us to be.
我这就进去拿铲子来
I'm gonna go inside and I'm gonna get a shovel.
- 带了两件黑衬衫  - 有 长官
- Got two black shirts?  - Sir.
- 两条黑裤子  - 有 长官
- Two pair black pants?  - Yes, sir.
- 一双黑靴子  - 有 长官
- One pair black boots?  - Sir.
- 两双黑袜子  - 有 长官
- Two pair black socks?  - Sir.
- 一件黑外套  - 有 长官
- One black jacket?  - Sir.
- 三百美元的个人丧葬费  - 有 长官
- $300 personal burial money?  - Yes, sir.
好吧
All right.
你太老了 肥佬
You're too old, fat man.
你奶子太大了 滚出我的门廊
Your tits are too big. Get the fuck off my porch.
Bob Bob
Bob! Bob!
就像准备被射上太空的猴子
Like a monkey ready to be shot into space.
太空猴
Space monkey.
准备为更崇高的事业牺牲自己
Ready to sacrifice himself for the greater good.
你他妈的太老了 肥猪
You are too fucking old, fatty!
还有你 你他妈
And you... You're too fucking...
毛太黄了
blond!
滚 你俩都给我滚
Get out of here, the both of you!
之后就这样继续着
And so it went.
听好了 蛆虫们
Listen up, maggots.
你并不特别
You are not special.
你不是什么美丽独一无二的雪花
You are not a beautiful or unique snowflake.
你就是跟其他一切一样正在腐烂的有机物
You are the same decaying organic matter as everything else.
泰勒给自己建了一支军队
Tyler built himself an army.
我们都是迎合这世界的活生生一坨屎
We are the all-singing, all-dancing crap of the world.
我们都是同一堆粪里的一部分
We are all part of the same compost heap.
泰勒·德顿为什么要建一支军队
Why was Tyler Durden building an army?
有什么目的 为了什么更崇高的事业
To what purpose? For what greater good?
只要是泰勒 我们就完全信任
In Tyler we trusted.
不对 不对
No, no, no, no.
他说"工作不代表你"的时候 我就感觉 "还真是"
When he was like, "You are not your job," I was like, "Yeah!"
- 嘿 这是干什么  - 嘿
- Hey, what's all this?  - Hey!
好了
Ok!
- 怎么了这是  - 我们要好好庆祝一下
- What's going on?  - We're celebrating.
- 庆祝什么  - 去吧
- What are we celebrating?  - Go on.
- 嘿  - 我来帮你拿
- Hey.  - Let me get that for you.
美味依旧 百事可乐 新一代饮料
Same great taste. Pepsi. Generation Next.
突发新闻
嘘
Shh!
调查人员已经来到现场
Investigators are on the scene right now.
直播
帕克莫里斯大楼
西富兰克林
等等 警察局长Jacobs刚到现场
Hold on. Police Commissioner Jacobs has just arrived.
帕克莫里斯大楼
西富兰克林
局长 局长
Commissioner, commissioner,
能否告诉我们这是怎么回事
could you please tell us what you think has happened here?
我们相信本案和近期市内多起蓄意破坏行为有关
We believe this is one of many recent acts of vandalism around the city
直播
帕克莫里斯大楼
西富兰克林
似乎和一个地下搏击俱乐部有关
somehow related to underground boxing clubs.
我们会协作展开缜密调查
We will be coordinating a rigorous investigation.
直播
帕克莫里斯大楼
西富兰克林
刚刚采访的是刚来到这场大约一小时前发生的
That was Police Commissioner Jacobs who just arrived on the scene here
四级火灾现场的Jacobs警察局长
on a four-alarm fire that broke out about an hour ago...
- 她好辣啊  - Lauren Sanchez在帕克莫里斯大楼给您带来的现场报道
- She's hot.  - Live from Park Morris Builing, Lauren Sanchez.
直播
帕克莫里斯大楼
西富兰克林
交回到演播室
Back to the studio.
早些时候
帕克莫里斯大楼
西富兰克林
好耶
Yeah!
- 我靠  - 好耶
- Holy shit!  - Yeah!
早些时候
你们这帮人都他妈干了什么
What the fuck did you guys do?
长官 大破坏计划的第一条规定是 不能有疑问 长官
Sir, the first rule of project Mayhem is you do not ask questions, sir.
打击犯罪不会一夜之间获得胜利
The victory in the war against crime will not come overnight.
需要奉献和坚持
It will take dedication and commitment,
最重要的是 合作
and most of all, cooperation.
街头比以前安全了 市内的秩序还是有希望的
Streets are safer now. There is hope in the inner city.
- 然而这只是开始  - 我去上个厕所
- However, this is only a beginning...  - I gotta take a piss.
前程漫漫 这还只是第一步
These are the first steps in a long journey.
- 所以我们才建立了希望计划  - Bob
- That is why we have created Project Hope...  - Bob.
通过预防犯罪和加强执法来维持治安
...helping others with prevention and enforcement.
希望计划需要警方
Project Hope will be a joint effort
和社区领导的共同努力
between the police and community leaders.
它将是打击犯罪的有力新武器
It will be a powerful new weapon in the war against crime.
把他的蛋蛋包起来 Bob
Wrap it around the top of his Hacky Sack, Bob.
靠 他的蛋冰冰凉的
Man! His balls are ice-cold.
听着 你要取消你那缜密的调查
Hi. You're gonna call off your rigorous investigation.
你要公开声明根本没什么地下组织 否则
You're gonna publicly state there is no underground group, or
- 这几位会割掉你的蛋蛋  - 不要
- these guys are gonna take your balls.  - No!
一颗寄给<纽约时报> 一颗寄给<洛城时报>
They'll send one to the New York Times and one to the LA Times,
媒体会让你名"蛋"天下
press will release out.
听着 你要追查的人都是你赖以生存的人
Look, the people you are after are the people you depend on.
我们给你做饭 帮你倒垃圾 为你转接电话
We cook your meals. We haul your trash. We connect your calls.
开救护车送你去医院 你睡觉时还替你看门
We drive your ambulances. We guard you while you sleep.
别他妈惹我们
Do not fuck with us.
留你两个蛋
Ball check!
普莱斯曼酒店
卸货区
当心卡车
Bob 你走这边
Bob, this way.
我们走
Let's go.
"我是Jack强烈的被排斥感"
"I am Jack's inflamed sense of rejection."
嘿
Hey!
好样的
Yeah!
我想要射杀每一只不肯交配
I felt like putting a bullet between the eyes of every panda
来延续种族的熊猫
that wouldn't screw to save its species.
我想打开油轮的倾泻阀
I wanted to open the dump valves on oil tankers
将那些我永远都看不到的法国海滩厚厚地掩埋
and smother all those French beaches I'd never see.
我想要吞枪自杀
I wanted to breathe smoke.
你着了什么魔 疯小子
Where did you go, psycho boy?
我想摧毁美好的东西
I felt like destroying something beautiful.
- 快他妈带他去医院  - 好的
- Get him to a fucking hospital.  - Yeah.
别担心 Durden先生 机场的长期寄停车
Don't worry, Mr. Durden. Airport parking. Long term.
您先请 Durden先生
After you, Mr. Durden.
您先请
After you.
宠物死后 请妥善烹调
- 有什么心事 亲爱的  - 没有
- Something on your mind, dear?  - No.
好吧 有 为什么不告诉我大破坏计划的事
Alright, yeah. Why wasn't I told about Project Mayhem?
大破坏计划的第一条规定是不能有疑问
First rule of Project Mayhem is you do not ask questions.
- 你在说什么  - 为什么不一开始就让我参与
- What are you talking about?  - Why didn't you include me in the beginning?
搏击俱乐部就是开始啊
Fight Club was the beginning.
现在搬出地下室 就成了大破坏计划
Now it's left the basements and it's Project Mayhem.
是我们一起成立的搏击俱乐部 还记得吗
You and I started Fight Club together. You remember that?
它是你的 也同样是我的
It's as much mine as it is yours, you know.
你不爽是因为咱俩
Is this about you and me?
是啊 我以为我们是一起合作的啊
Yeah. I thought we were doing this together?
你完全搞错了 它并不属于我们
You're missing the point. This does not belong to us.
- 我们并不特别  - 滚你的吧 你应该告诉我的
- We are not special.  - Fuck that. You... you should have told me.
嘿 泰勒
Hey, Tyler!
- 我靠 泰勒  - 你想怎样
- Goddamn it, Tyler!  - What do you want?
写份目的陈述吗 发你邮箱吗
A statement of purpose? Should I email you?
帮你加进待处理事项清单里吗
Should I put this on your action item-list?
- 听着  - 参与程度完全取决于你自己
- Oh, look...  - You decide your level of involvement!
我当然要参与 我想先搞清楚
I will! I wanna know certain things first!
- 大破坏计划的第一条规定  - 给我闭嘴
- The first rule of Project Mayhem...  - Shut up!
- 我要知道你在想什么  - 你要知道个屁
- I wanna know what you're thinking.  - Fuck what you know!
你得把你知道的通通忘了 这才是你该解决的
You need to forget about what you know, that's your problem.
忘了你自以为清楚的生活 友谊
Forget waht you think you know about life, about friendship,
尤其是把你和我的事忘干净
and especially about you and me.
你 你这是什么意思 什么
Wha... what is that supposed to mean? What...
你干什么呢
What are you doing?
伙计们 你们死前的愿望是什么
Guys, what will you wish you'd done before you die?
- 画幅自画像  - 盖栋房子
- Paint a self-portrait.  - Build a house.
- 你呢  - 我 我不知道 没有 什么都没有
- And you?  - I... I don't know. Nothing. Nothing.
- 别闹了 回到右车道  - 你必须回答这个问题
- Come on! Get in the right lane.  - You have to answer this question!
如果你现在就要死了 你会怎么评价你的一生
If you die right now, how would you feel about your life?
我不知道 我觉得我活得糟透了
I don't know! I wouldn't feel anything good about my life.
这就是你想听的吗 满意了吧
Is that what you want to hear me say? Fine.
- 别闹了  - 还不够好
- Come on!  - Not good enough.
别他妈发疯了 泰勒
Stop fucking around! Tyler!
天哪
Jesus Christ!
该死 该死 去你妈的
Goddamn it! Goddamn it! Fuck you!
去他妈的搏击俱乐部 去他妈的玛拉 我受够你这套了
Fuck Fight Club. Fuck Marla! I am sick of all your shit!
好吧 兄弟 好吧
OK, man. OK.
- 别再胡闹了 握住方向盘  - 看看你
- Quit screwing around. Take the wheel!  - Look at you!
- 握住方向盘  - 看看你自己 真他妈可悲
- Take the wheel!  - Look at you! You're fucking pathetic!
为什么 你说什么呢
Why? Why? What are you talking about?
你觉得我为什么要炸掉你的公寓
Why do you think I blew up your condo?
什么
What?
彻底堕落不是参加个周末静修 也不是什么他妈的研讨会
Hitting bottom isn't a weekend retreat. It's not a goddamn seminar.
别再想控制一切 放手吧
Stop trying to control everything and just let go!
- 放手  - 好吧 好
- Let go!  - All right. Fine.
好吧
Fine.
我从没出过车祸
I'd never been in a car accident.
这肯定是我统计报告里
This must have been what all those people felt like
那些车里乘客的感受
before I filed them as statistics in my reports.
爽爆了
Goddamn!
我们刚刚有了一次永生难忘的体验
We've just had a near-life experience!
在我眼中的世界
In the world I see,
你在洛克菲勒中心废墟周围的大峡谷森林里
you're stalking elk through the Grand Canyon forests
洛克菲勒中心是美国纽约曼哈顿商业中心
追寻麋鹿的踪迹
around the ruins of Rockefeller Center.
你会穿着一辈子都不会坏的皮衣
You'll wear leather clothes that will last you the rest of your life.
你沿着缠绕着西尔斯大厦的藤蔓攀登
You'll climb the thick kudzu vines that wrap the Sears Tower.
西尔斯大厦是位于美国芝加哥市中心的前世界最高大厦
往下看的时候 你会看到一个个微小人影
And when you look down, you'll see tiny figures pounding corn,
在某个废弃高速公路
laying strips of venison
空荡荡的拼车道上打谷晒肉
in the empty car-pool lane of some abandoned superhighway.
早日康复 兄弟
Feel better, champ.
然后
And then...
泰勒
Tyler?
泰勒走了
...Tyler was gone.
我睡着了吗
Was I asleep?
人 类 牺 牲
我有睡着吗
Had I slept?
你不是什么美丽独一无二的雪花 明白吗
You are not a beautiful or unique snowflake, do you understand me?
这栋房子仿佛有了生命
The house had become a living thing,
这么多人在里面流汗呼吸让屋子里充满湿气
wet inside from so many people sweating and breathing.
这么多人活动 房子仿佛也在动
So many people moving, the house moved.
泰勒星球
Planet Tyler.
我只能贴着墙走
I had to hug the walls,
困在这帮上了发条的太空猴里
trapped inside this clockwork of space monkeys.
你怎么能在这儿抽烟 你知道这房子里有他妈多少乙醚吗
You can't be smoking here! You know how much ether we have in this fucking house?
有组织有纪律地吃喝工作睡觉
Cooking and working and sleeping in teams.
稍等
Hang on a second.
假情报
恶作剧
特鲁里大街
艾伯特大道
一切尽在掌握中 长官
It's under control, sir.
特鲁里大街
泰勒在哪儿
Where's Tyler?
长官 大破坏计划的第一条规定是不能有
Sir, the first rule of Project Mayhem is you do not...
对 规定 好吧
Right. The... OK.
我又孤身一人了
I'm all alone.
我爸不要我 泰勒也抛下我
My father dumped me. Tyler dumped me.
"我是Jack伤透了的心"
"I am Jack's broken heart."
只有泰勒知道大破坏计划的下一步是什么
What comes next in Project Mayhem only Tyler knows.
第二条规定是不能有疑问
The second rule is you do not ask questions.
他妈的离我远点儿 他妈的滚远点儿
Get the fuck away from me! Get the fuck away from me!
这些都是什么人啊
Who are all these people?
珮波街肥皂公司的员工
The Paper Street Soap Company.
我能进去吗
Can I come in?
他不在这儿
He's not here.
什么
What?
泰勒不在这儿
Tyler isn't here.
泰勒走了
Tyler went away.
泰勒不回来了
Tyler's gone.
天哪 快帮忙啊
Jesus! Get some help!
好了 放他下来
Alright, lay him down!
中了两处枪伤 他妈的腾点儿地方啊
Two gunshot wounds coming through! Make some fucking room!
怎么了 这是怎么了
What happened? What happened?
我们当时在执行任务
We were on assignment.
本来计划好的一石二鸟
We were supposed to kill two birds with one stone.
毁掉一座公司的艺术品
Destroy a piece of corporate art...
拿铁雷霆行动 开始
Operation Latte Thunder. Go!
顺便毁掉一个连锁咖啡厅
...and trash a franchise coffee bar.
一切都安排好了 长官
We had it all worked out, sir.
- 一直挺顺利 直到  - 警察 不许动
- It went smooth until...  - Police! Freeze!
- 直到什么  - 他们开枪射中了Bob
- What?  - They shot Bob.
- 正中脑袋  - 混蛋条子
- They shot him in the head.  - Fucking pigs!
老天
Oh, God!
那帮王八蛋
Those motherfuckers!
你们这帮蠢货
You morons.
你们带着面罩满大街乱跑炸东西
You run around in ski masks trying to blow things up?
还想有什么好下场
What did you think was gonna happen?
好了 赶快 我们得销毁证据 把尸体处理掉
OK, quick! We gotta get rid of the evidence. We gotta get rid of his body!
埋了他
Bury him.
什么
What?
把他抬到花园埋了
Take him to the garden and bury him.
别傻站着 赶紧动起来
Come on, people, let's go!
嘿 都他妈放手 别碰他
Hey, get the fuck off! Get away from him!
你们说什么呢
What are you talking about?
这他妈不是什么证据 他是个人
This isn't fucking piece of evidence. This is a person.
他是我的朋友 你们谁也甭想把他埋在什么破花园里
He's a friend of mine and you're not gonna bury him in the fucking garden!
他是为大破坏计划牺牲的 长官
He was killed serving Project Mayhem, sir.
- 他是Bob啊  - 但长官 在
- This is Bob.  - But, sir, in...
在大破坏计划里 我们没有名字
in Project Mayhem, we have no names.
你们给我听好了
Now, you listen to me.
他是个人 他有名字 他叫Robert Paulsen 听懂了吗
This is a man and he has a name, and it's Robert Paulsen, OK?
Robert Paulsen
Robert Paulsen?
他是个人 现在却因我们而死 好吗 你们懂了吗
He's a man, and he's dead now because of us, alright? Do you understand that?
我懂了
I understand.
大破坏计划中的成员 为其献出生命后就有名字
In death, a member of Project Mayhem has a name.
他的名字是Robert Paulsen
His name is Robert Paulsen.
他的名字 是Robert Paulsen
His name... is Robert Paulsen.
他的名字是Robert Paulsen
His name is Robert Paulsen.
- 拜托 你们别这样  - 他的名字是Robert Paulsen
- Come on, guys. Please. Stop it.  - His name is Robert Paulsen.
他的名字是Robert Paulsen 他的名字
His name is Robert Paulsen. His name...
闭嘴 这事到此为止
Shut up! This is all over with!
他的名字是Robert Paulsen
His name is Robert Paulsen.
从     洛杉矶
到     芝加哥
从     达拉斯
到     亚特兰大
登机牌
乘客名    T Y L E R
泰勒
Tyler?
不 我是纵火组的Stern警探
No, this is Detective Stern of the Arson Unit.
我需要你到局里来一趟
I need to see you in my office...
我去了所有泰勒票根上的城市 一个酒吧找到另一个酒吧
I went to all the cities on Tyler's used ticket stubs, bar-hopping.
不知道为什么
I didn't know how or why,
那么多的酒吧 我就是知道应该进哪家
but I could look at 50 different bars, and somehow I just knew.
我在找泰勒·德顿 有非常重要的事要跟他说
I'm looking for Tyler Durden. It's very important that I talk to him.
我也希望能帮到你
I wish I could help you,
长官
sir.
我去的每个城市
Every city I went to,
只要我一下飞机
as soon as I set foot off the plane,
就知道附近有搏击俱乐部
I knew a Fight Club was close.
嘿 嘿
Hey! Hey!
出租车
Taxi!
看着我的脸 我也是其中的一员
Look at my face. I'm a member, you know.
我只想知道你有没有见到泰勒
I just need to know if you've seen Tyler.
我不能
I'm not exposed to
将这种讯息透露给你
bespeak any such information to you,
即便我之前已经说过你想要的讯息 现在的我
nor would I, even if I had said information you want at this juncture...
也不能说
be able.
- 你就是个白痴  - 恐怕我得请你离开了
- You're a moron.  - I'm afraid I have to ask you to leave.
泰勒一直忙着
Tyler had been busy...
在全国各地建立分会
setting up franchises all over the country.
我睡着了吗 我有睡着吗
Was I asleep? Had I slept?
究竟泰勒是我的梦魇 还是我是他的梦魇
Is Tyler my bad dream, or am I Tyler's?
- 我们刚到了传言  - 什么传言
- We've just heard the stories.  - What kind of stories?
没人知道他长什么样子
Nobody knows what he looks like.
他每三年就做一次面部整形手术
He has facial reconstructive surgery every three years.
这是我听过最蠢的笑话
That's the stupidest thing I've ever heard.
迈阿密真的也有搏击俱乐部了吗
Is it true about Fight Club in Miami?
Durden先生是在建立军队吗
Is Mr. Durden building an army?
我活在一种似曾相识的状态中
I was living in a state of perpetual Deja vu.
我去的每个地方 我都感觉自己去过
Everywhere I went, I felt I'd already been there.
就像在跟踪一个隐形人一样
It was like following an invisible man.
已经凝固的血液味道
The smell of dried blood.
肮脏的赤足脚印凌乱地叠加在一起
Dirty, bare footprints circling each other.
还有炸鸡一般的汗臭味
That aroma of old sweat, like fried chicken.
地板上还残留着前一晚激斗的余温
The feel of a floor still warm from a fight the night before.
我总是就比泰勒晚一步
I was always just one step behind Tyler.
他的名字是Robert Paulsen 他的名字是Robert Paulsen 他的
His name is Robert Paulsen. His name is Robert Paulsen. His...
欢迎回来 长官
Welcome back, sir.
别来无恙
How have you been?
你认识我吗
Do you know me?
- 这是个测试吗 长官  - 不 不是测试
- Is this a test, sir?  - No. This is not a test.
你上周四来过了啊
You were in here last Thursday.
周四
Thursday?
你当时就站在那儿 问我这里的安保好不好
You were standing exactly where you are now, asking how good security is.
固若金汤 长官
It's tight as a drum, sir.
你觉得我是谁
Who do you think I am?
- 你确定这不是测试吗  - 不 这不是测试
- Are you sure this isn't a test?  - No, this is not a test.
你是Durden先生
You're Mr. Durden.
是你给了我这个
You're the one who gave me this.
请将您的座椅复原为竖直状态并固定
Please return your seat backs to their full upright and locked position.
- 喂  - 玛拉 是我
- Yeah?  - Marla, it's me.
- 我们做过吗  - 做过什么
- Have we ever done it?  - Done what?
- 我们上过床吗  - 这是什么傻逼问题
- Have we ever had sex?  - What kind of stupid question is that?
这问题傻逼是因为我们做过还是没做过
Is it stupid because the answer's yes or because the answer's no?
- 你是在耍我吗  - 不 玛拉 我真的需要知道
- Is this a trick?  - No. Marla, I need to know...
你想知道我觉得我们只是在滚床单还是做爱吗
You wanna know if I think we were just having sex or making love?
- 我们真的做过爱了  - 你认为我们是在做爱吗
- We did make love?  - Is that what you're calling it?
回答我的问题 玛拉 拜托 我们到底做没做过
Ju... just answer the question, Marla, please! Did we do it or not?
你干了我 又不搭理我 你爱我 转脸又讨厌我
You fuck me, then snub me. You love me, you hate me.
你一会儿感情丰富 紧接着又变成个大混蛋
You show me your sensitive side, then you turn into a total asshole.
这样形容我们的关系够准确吧 泰勒
Is that a pretty accurate description of our relationship, Tyler?
机舱压力骤减
We have just lost cabin pressure.
- 你刚说什么  - 你抽什么风
- What did you just say?  - What is wrong with you?
- 你刚叫我什么 再说一遍  - 泰勒·德顿
- What did you just call me? Say my name!  - Tyler Durden.
泰勒·德顿 你个死变态 到底怎么回事
Tyler Durden, you fucking freak! What's going on?
- 我这就过去  - 别 等等 玛拉 我不在家
- I'm coming over!  - No, wait Marla, I'm not there!
你违背誓言了
You broke your promise.
- 天哪 泰勒  - 你他妈的跟她说我了
- Jesus, Tyler.  - You fucking talked to her about me.
这他妈到底怎么回事
What the fuck is going on here?
我只要求你做一件事 这么简单的一件事
I ask you for one thing. One simple thing.
为什么人们会把我当成你
Why do people think that I'm you?
回答我啊
Answer me!
坐下
Sit.
回答我 为什么人们会把我当成你
Answer me. Why do people think that I'm you?
我觉得你知道答案
I think you know.
- 不 我不知道  - 不 你知道
- No, I don't.  - Yes, you do.
怎么可能会有人把咱俩搞混
Why would anyone possibly confuse you with me?
我 我 我不知道
I... I... I don't know.
- 你明白了  - 不会吧
- You got it.  - No.
- 别惹我们  - 说出来
- Do not fuck with us!  - Say it.
因为
Because...
说出来啊
Say it!
因为我们是同一个人
Because we're the same person.
对了
That's right.
我们都是迎合这世界的活生生一坨屎
We are the all-singing, all-dancing crap...
我不明白
I don't understand this.
你想找到一种改变你生活的方式
You're looking for a way to change your life.
但你一个人办不到
You could not do this on your own.
你一直想要变成的样子 就是我
All the ways you wish you could be, that's me.
我长得像你希望的样子 做爱像你希望的样子
I look like you wanna look, fuck like you wanna fuck,
我聪明 有能力 最重要的是
I am smart, capable and, most importantly,
我在你所有拘手绑脚的事情上都无拘无束
I'm free in all the ways that you are not.
噢 不
Oh, no.
- 泰勒不在这儿 泰勒走了 泰勒不回来了  - 什么
- Tyler's not here. Tyler went away. Tyler's gone.  - What?
- 这不可能  - 可能
- This isn't possible.  - No.
- 这太疯狂了  - 人们每天都这样
- This is crazy.  - People do it every day.
他们自言自语 一厢情愿地看自己
They talk to themselves. They see themselves as they'd like to be.
但他们没有你的勇气去实现这一切
They don't have the courage you have to just run with it.
当然 你内心还在挣扎 所以有时候你还是你自己
Naturally, you're still wrestling with it, so sometimes you're still you.
我们应该找机会再打一架
We should do this again sometime.
其他时候 你想象自己在看着我
Other times, you imagine yourself watching me.
如果这是你来搏击俱乐部的第一晚 就必须打
If this is your first night at Fight Club, you have to fight.
渐渐地 你让自己变成了
Little by little, you're just letting yourself become...
泰勒·德顿
Tyler Durden.
工作不能代表你 银行存款不能代表你
You are not your job or how much money you have in the bank!
- 不 你有栋房子  - 以你名义租的
- No. You have a house.  - Rented in your name.
你有工作 有你的生活
You have jobs, you have a whole life.
你晚上做兼职 因为你睡不着
You have night jobs 'cause you can't sleep.
- 或者整晚做肥皂  - 你和玛拉上床 泰勒
- Or you stay up and make soap.  - You're fucking Marla, Tyler.
呃 严格来讲 是你跟她上床 不过对她都没差
Uh, technically, you are fucking Marla. But it's all the same to her.
我的天哪
Oh, my God.
现在看到我们的困境了吧
Now you see our dilemma.
她知道得太多了
She knows too much.
我觉得咱们得谈谈 她可能会妨碍到我们达成目标
I think we're gonna have to talk about how this might compromise our goals.
你什么意思
Wha... what are you saying?
这简直是胡扯
This is... this is bullshit.
胡扯 我不会听你的 你疯了
This is bullshit! I'm not listening to this. You are insane!
不 疯的是你
No. You're insane.
我们已经没有时间说这些废话了
And we simply do not have time for this crap.
这就是所谓的胶卷切换
It's called a changeover.
电影继续如常放映 观众们却都毫不知情
The movie goes on, and nobody in the audience has any idea.
- 先生 您要退房了吗  - 对 把账单给我
- Sir! Are you checking out?  - Yeah. Bi... bill me.
请您先在这张电话清单上签字确认
I need you to initial this list of phone calls, please.
这些是什么时候打的
When were these made?
- 都列在那里呢 先生 凌晨2点到3点半之间  - 不 我没
- It's right there, sir. Between 2:00 and 3:30 this morning.  - No, I...
我每晚都更早睡觉了吗
Have I been going to bed earlier every night?
我后来真的睡着了吗
Have I been sleeping later?
我变成泰勒的时间越来越长了吗
Have I been Tyler longer and longer?
有人在吗
Is anybody here?
似曾相识 一切从头开始
Deja vu, all over again.
只要肥皂够多 想炸飞什么都行
With enough soap, one could blow up just about anything.
天哪
Oh, my God.
- 1888号  - 请问你是哪里
- 1888.  - Who am I calling?
富兰克林街1888号 这里是物业部
1888 Franklin. This is maintenance.
你好 喂
Hello? Hello?
富兰克林街1888号
富兰克林街1888号吗
1888 Franklin Street?
对 有事吗
Yes. Can I help you?
- 还在吗  - 在 在
- Hello?  - Yeah, yeah.
呃 我要马上跟你们主管谈
Uh... I need to talk to your supervisor right away.
- 我就是  - 好 听我说
- Speaking.  - OK, listen to me.
你们大楼可能马上会发生很可怕的事 你们得
I think something really terrible is about to happen to your building. You have got...
一切尽在掌握中 长官
It's under control, sir.
- 你说什么  - 别担心我们 长官 相当可靠
- Excuse me? - Don't worry about us, sir. We're solid.
2160号
2160.
富尔顿大道2160号
玛拉 玛拉 嘿 玛  等等
Marla! Marla! Hey, Mar... wait!
等等 我有话跟你说 玛拉 玛拉
Wait! I gotta talk to you! Marla! Marla!
- 你那些变态光头手下用他妈扫帚打我  - 我知道
- Your whack-out bald freaks hit me with a fucking broom!  - Oh, I know.
差点弄断我胳膊
They almost broke my arm!
他们用碱把指纹烧掉 这些烂事儿简直难以置信
They were burning their fingertips with lye. These things are unbelievable.
听着 听着 你可能需要极度信任我才能了解事实
Look. Look, Listen, it's gonna take a tremendous act of faith on your part,
但你必须听我说
but got to hear me out.
好 你就满嘴跑火车吧
OK, here comes an avalanche of bullshit.
再相信我一点
A little more faith than that.
不 听着 我不想听你说任何话
No, listen, I don't wanna hear anything you have to say.
你完全有权利这么
You have every right to be...
我 我要一杯咖啡就好 谢谢
I'll... I'll just have a coffee, thanks.
长官 你点什么都免费 长官
Sir, anything you order is free of charge, sir.
- 为什么免费  - 别问
- Why is it free of charge?  - Don't ask.
随便吧 呃 我要蛤蜊浓汤
Whatever. Uh... I'll have the clam chowder,
配烤土豆和其他全套的炸鸡 还有一个巧克力威风派
fried chicken with a baked potato with everything and a chocolate chiffon pie.
拜托 请上干净的食物
Clean food, please.
这样的话 长官 我建议这位女士不要点蛤蜊浓汤
In that case, sir, may I advise against the lady eating clam chowder?
那就不要蛤蜊浓汤 谢谢
No clam chowder. Thank you.
你有30秒时间
You got about 30 seconds.
我知道我的行为举止一直非常 非常奇怪
Well, I know that I've been acting very very strange, OK?
我 我明白你一定会感觉我是个两面人
I... I know that it's got to say there's two sides to me...
<化身博士><Dr. Jekyll and Mr. Hyde>是1941年的美国电影
主角Jekyll博士相信每个人都同时拥有两极化的个性
并以化学实验将自己身上邪恶的一面转化为Hyde先生犯下可怕的罪行
两面人 那你就是化身博士和混蛋先生
Two sides? You're Dr. Jekyll and Mr. Jackass.
你怎么说我都行 但我终于意识到一件非常 非常重要的事
I deserved that. But I... I've come to realized something very very important.
什么事
What?
直到现在我才弄明白我俩确切的关系
The full extent of our relationship wasn't really clear to me up until now,
具体原因我不细说了
for reasons I'm not go into.
但重点是我 我知道我一直没有好好对待你
But the important thing is I... I know that I haven't treated you so nice.
- 随你吧  - 不 不 不 15秒 再给我15秒 拜托
- Whatever.  - No. No. No. Fifteen seconds, fifteen seconds, please!
15秒 求你别说话
Fifteen seconds, don't open your mouth.
我想告诉你 我很抱歉
I'm trying to tell you that I'm sorry.
因为我现在明白了 我真的喜欢你 玛拉
Because what I've come to realize is that I... I really like you, Marla.
- 真的吗  - 千真万确
- You do?  - I really do.
我很在乎你 我不想你因为我发生任何不好的事
I care about you and I don't want anything bad to happen to you because of me.
玛拉 你的生命危在旦夕
Marla, your life is in danger.
- 什么  - 你得离开城里一段时间
- What?  - You need to leave town for a while.
不要去任何大城市 就去露营或者
Get out of any major city, and just go camping or something...
你真是个疯子
You're an insane person.
不 我把你卷入了可怕的事情 马上就要发生了
No. I've involved you in something terrible, that's about to happen...
不 闭嘴
No. Shut up!
- 你不安全  - 闭嘴
- You're not safe.  - Shut up!
- 听着 我努力过了 泰勒 我真的努力了  - 我知道
- Listen, I tried, Tyler. I really tried.  - I know you did.
你的某些特质我很喜欢
There are things about you I like.
你聪明 幽默 床上功夫一流
You're smart. You're funny. You're spectacular in bed.
但 你实在让人无法忍受
But... you're intolerable.
你有很严重的情绪问题
You have very serious emotional problems,
非常严重的问题 你该去寻求专业医生的帮助
deep-seated problems for which you should seek professional help.
我知道 我很抱歉
I know, and I'm sorry.
对 你很抱歉 我很抱歉 大家都很抱歉 但
Yeah, you're sorry, I'm sorry, everyone's sorry, but...
我不能再这样下去了
I can't do this anymore.
我不能 也不会这样了
I can't. I won't.
我要走了
I'm gone.
你不能走 玛拉 你不安全
You can't leave, Marla! You're not safe!
- 玛拉 你还没明白  - 不 放开我
- Marla, you don't understand!  - No! Leave me alone!
- 玛拉 我是想保护你  - 走开 不 放开我
- Marla, I am trying to protect you!  - Just go awany. No, let go of me!
- 我再也不想看见你  - 没问题 如果这是代价的话
- I don't ever wanna see you again!  - That's fine. If that's what it takes...
来 在这儿等着
Here, wait right here.
就停在这儿 别按了 别按了
Hold it right there! Shut up! Shut up!
直达巴士
拿着这些钱 乘这巴士走吧
Take this money and get on this bus.
我保证以后再也不骚扰你
And I promise you I would never bother you again.
别他妈按了
Shut up!
求你上车吧 上车吧
Please get on the bus. Please get on the bus.
- 你为什么要这么做  - 他们觉得你是个威胁
- Why are you doing this?  - They think you're kind of a threat.
我现在没办法解释 相信我就是了
I... I can't explain it right now. Just trust me!
要是我看到你的目的地 你就会有危险
If I see where you're going, you will not be safe.
我不会还你钱的 就当是你欠我的混账债
I'm not paying this back. I consider it asshole tax.
好 记住 至少这几天都远离大城市 好吗
Fine. Remember, stay out of major cities for at least a couple of days, OK?
泰勒
Tyler...
你是我一生中遇到的最糟的事
You're the worst thing that ever happened to me.
你好 我需要你逮捕我
Hello. I need you to arrest me.
我是一个恐怖组织的头目
I am the leader of a terrorist organization
策划了众多市内的破坏公物及人身攻击行动
responsible for numerous acts of vandalism and assault all over the city.
审讯室B
使用中
在大城区 我们大概有几百名成员
In the metropolitan area, we probably have a couple hundred members.
五六个其他大城市也已经设立了分部
Chapters have sprung up in five or six other major cities already.
美国国民银行
圣彼得堡 新英格兰 布拉德福德
审核通过
总体建筑工程
布拉德福德 富尔顿大道2160号
部分上下层计划以及南人行道计划
维斯塔信用卡
北侧塔楼及广场
艾美瑞广场 6868号
这是一个严密编制的组织
This is a tightly regimented organization
很多基层小组成员可以完全不依赖头目直接行动
with many cells capable of operating completely independent of central leadership.
听着 你们去那房子看看吧 珮波街1537号
Look, go to the house, OK? 1537 Paper Street.
那是我们的总部
That's our headquarters.
在后面的花园里
In the back, buried in the garden,
埋着Robert Paulsen的尸体
you'll find the body of Robert Paulsen.
在地下室里 有一些浴缸
In the basement, you're gonna find some bathtubs
最近一直用来制造大量的硝化甘油
that have been used very recently to make large quantities of nitroglycerin.
我相信他们是计划
I believe the plan
炸掉这些信用卡公司的总部
is to blow up the headquarters of these credit-card companies
和天合汽车集团大厦
and the TRW building.
为什么选这些大楼 为什么是信用卡公司
Why these buildings? Why credit-card companies?
如果债务记录都被消除 我们都回到起点
If you erase the debt record, then we all go back to zero.
这样能制造彻底的大混乱
You'll create total chaos.
让他说下去 我得去打个电话
Keep him talking. I need to make a phone call.
我太佩服你的勇气了
I really admire what you're doing.
- 什么  - 你真是够胆下这种命令
- What?  - You're a brave man to order this.
你是个天才 长官
You're a genius, sir.
你说过无论谁阻碍大破坏计划 即便是你
You said if anyone ever interferes with Project Mayhem, even you,
我们也得阉了他
we gotta get his balls.
- 反抗也没用  - 你真是个了不起的人物 Durden先生
- It's useless to fight.  - You're really a powerful gesture, Mr. Durden.
- 你树立了好榜样  - 你们在铸成大错 伙计们
- You set quite an example.  - You're making a big mistake, fellows!
- 你说过你会这么说  -  我不是泰勒·德顿
- You said you'd say that.  - I'm not Tyler Durden!
你告诉我们你也会这么说
You told us you'd say that too.
好吧 我是泰勒·德顿
All right. I am Tyler Durden.
听着 我向你们直接下达命令
Listen to me. I'm giving you a direct order.
马上停止这个任务
We're aborting this mission right now.
你说过你肯定会这么说
You said you would definitely say that.
放开我
Let me go!
你们都他妈疯了吗 你们是警察啊
Are you fucking out of your minds? You're police officers!
有人计时吗
Somebody timing this?
- 不要 不要  - 给我闭嘴
- No! No...  - Keep your mouth shut.
该死
Shit!
- 有一些信息已经查实  - 嗯哼
- Some of this information checks out.  - Uh- huh?
- 我们这就去珮波街的那个房子看看吧  - 马上就来  - 好
- Let's go over to that house on Paper Street.  - Be right there.  - OK.
嘿 等等
Hey, wait!
- 你们搞得定吗  - 我按住他了
- You got that?  - I got him.
长官 我们必须这么做 别反抗了
Sir, we have to do this. Stop fighting!
橡皮筋在哪儿呢
Where's the rubber band?
放开我 他妈的把刀放下 放下
Get away from me! Drop that fucking knife! Drop it!
退后 你俩现在都给我脸朝地趴下
Back up. Face down on the floor both of you right now!
趴下
Get down on the floor!
谁他妈先从这扇门出来就
First person that comes out of this fucking door gets a...
就等着吃子弹吧 懂吗
gets a lead salad! Do you understand?
警察局
滚开 滚开
Get away! Stay away!
我一直跑
I ran.
跑到肌肉酸痛 血管肿胀
I ran until my muscles burned and my veins pumped battery acid.
然后我继续跑
Then I ran some more.
富兰克林街
你他妈干嘛呢 穿着裤衩儿他妈到处跑
What the fuck are you doing, fuck running around in your underpants?
老兄 你像个疯子
Man, you look like a crazy person!
不 我看穿你了 我知道你的计划了
No. I'm onto you. I know what's going on here.
那快来吧 我给咱们找了个绝佳的观景点
Well, come on, then. I got us a great place to watch from.
花钱才能看到的
It'll be like pay-per-view.
车库电梯
上帝
Oh, Christ.
你现在怎么办
Now what are you doing?
- 我要阻止这一切  - 为什么
- I'm stopping this. - Why?
- 这是你做的最伟大的事  - 不 我不能让它发生
- The greatest thing you've ever done. - No, I can't let this happen.
你知道另外10栋大楼里也都有炸弹呢
You know there are 10 other bombs in 10 other buildings.
去你妈的 大破坏计划什么时候成谋杀了
God damn it, since when is Project Mayhem about murder?
大楼都是空的 保安和物业都是我们的人
The buildings are empty. Security and maintenance, all our people.
我们没有要杀任何人 我们是在解放他们
We're not killing anyone, man. We're setting them free!
Bob死了 他们一枪轰了他的脑袋
Bob is dead. They shot him in the head.
你要做蛋卷 总得碎几个鸡蛋
You wanna make an omelet, you gotta break some eggs.
不 我不会听你说了 你根本就不存在
No. I'm not listening to you. You're not even there.
要是我就不这么做 除非我知道是哪条线
Wouldn't do that. Not unless I knew which wires were what.
如果你知道 那我就知道
If you know, then I know.
或者
Or...
也许我早知道你会知道 所以我一整天都在想着错误的线
maybe I knew you'd know, so I spent all day thinking about the wrong ones.
你觉得呢
You think?
天哪 别 别拔绿色的
Oh, heavens, no. Not the green one.
哪根都可以 别拔绿色的
Pull any one but the green one.
我要你别那么做
I asked you not to do that!
操
Fuck!
泰勒 离车远点儿
Tyler, get away from the van.
泰勒 我认真的 离车远点儿
Tyler, I'm not kidding! Get away from the van!
他妈该死的
Goddamn it!
好吧
Ok.
现在你要对站在400加仑硝化甘油旁边的
You are now firing a gun at your imaginary friend
想象出来的朋友开枪
near 400 gallons of nitroglycerin!
冷静 泰勒!泰勒!
Cool it, Tyler! Tyler!
哎哟 来嘛 别走
Aw, come on! Don't go!
怎样
What?
还有三分钟 尘埃落定
Three minutes. This is it.
回到开始
The beginning.
一切归零
Ground zero.
这应该就是我们故事开始的地方吧
I think this is about where we came in.
你要不要说两句来纪念这个伟大的时刻呢
Would you like to say a few words to mark the occasion?
你说什么
I'm sorry?
我还是想不到要说什么
I still can't think of anything.
啊 "还是"想不到哈
Ah. Flashback humor.
越来越刺激了
It's getting exciting now.
还有两分半钟 想想我们的成就吧 伙计
Two and a half. Think of everything we've accomplished, man.
透过这些窗户 我们将看到经济时代的崩塌
Out these windows, we will view the collapse of financial history.
离经济均衡又近了一步
One step closer to economic equilibrium.
- 她怎么在这儿  - 总要解决这个小事
- Why is she here?  - Tying up loose ends.
- 闭嘴  - 放我下来 你个秃头混蛋
- Shut up!  - Put me down, you bald-headed fuck!
我求你了 别这么做
I'm begging you, please don't do this.
不是我这么做 是我们一起做
I'm not doing this. We are doing this.
- 这是咱俩想要的  - 不 我不想这样
- This is what we want.  - No. I don't want this.
好吧 不过现在"你"已经没有意义了
Right. Except "you" is meaningless now.
我们得把你忘了
We have to forget about you.
- 你不过是我脑子里的声音  - 你也只是我脑子里的声音
- You're a voice in my head.  - You're a voice in mine!
- 你他妈只是个幻觉 为什么我摆脱不了你  - 你需要我
- You are a fucking illusion. Why can't I get rid of you?  - You need me.
不 我不需要 我真的再也不需要了
No. I don't. I really don't anymore.
嘿 是你创造的我
Hey! You created me.
我可不会造一个窝囊废自己来进行心理安慰
I didn't create some loser alter ego to make myself feel better.
- 负点儿责任吧你  - 我有
- Take some responsibility.  - I do.
这一切都是我的责任 我接受
I am responsible for all of it, and I accept that.
所以 求求你了 终止这一切
So, please, I'm begging you, please call this off.
我有让我们失望过吗
Have I ever let us down?
因为我 你成长了多少
How far have you come because of me?
我会带我们渡过难关
I will bring us through this.
跟往常一样 你不情不愿我也会拽着你
As always, I will carry you kicking and screaming,
最后你会感谢我的
and in the end you will thank me.
泰勒 我很感激你为我做的一切
Tyler, I'm grateful to you for everything that you've done for me.
但这太过分了 我不想这样
But this is too much. I don't want this.
那你要什么 回去做你那烂工作吗
What do you want? Wanna go back to your shit job?
在你那该死的公寓里看情景喜剧吗
Fucking condo world, watching sitcoms?
去你妈的 我才不要那么干
Fuck you! I won't do it.
老天 这不可能发生的
Oh, my God. This can't be happening.
事已至此 闭嘴吧
It's already done, so shut up!
- 还有60秒 直播正式开始  - 不
- 60 seconds till CRI.  - No.
我能想到办法的 能想到办法的 这都不是真的
I can figure this out. I can figure this out. This isn't even real.
你也不是真的 那枪甚至都不在你手里
You're not real. That gun is... That gun isn't even in your hand.
枪在我手上
The gun's in my hand.
嘿 好样的 不过也改变不了什么
Hey, good for you. It doesn't change a thing.
你干嘛拿枪顶着自己脑袋
Why do you wanna put a gun to your head?
不是我的头 泰勒
Not my head, Tyler.
是我们的头
Our head.
有意思
Interesting.
接下来你要怎么办呢 宜家男
Where are you going with this, IKEA boy?
嘿 这可是你和我
Hey. It's you and me.
朋友不是吗
Friends?
泰勒
Tyler,
我要你认真听我说
I want you to really listen to me.
好
OK.
我眼睛可盯着你呢
My eyes are open.
这是什么味道
What's that smell?
- 人都哪儿去了  - 不 怎么回事
- Where is everybody?  - Oh, no. What's going on?
Durden先生
Mr. Durden!
老天啊
Oh, my God!
长官
Sir!
你 你没事吧 长官
Are you... are you all right, sir?
噢 我没事
Oh, yeah, I'm OK.
你看起来糟透了 长官 发生什么事了
You look terrible, sir. What happened?
没什么 没问题了
Oh, nothing, it's no problem.
不 不 长官 他没开玩笑
No, no, no, sir. He's not kidding.
- 你的样子很吓人 需要医疗救助  - 我没事
- You look awful. You need medical assistance.  - I'm fine.
听着 我很好 什么问题都没有
Look, I'm fine. Everything's fine.
嗷 吃屎去吧
Ow! Take my shit!
- 放开她  - 老天爷啊
- Let her go.  - Christ Almighty!
是你
You!
嗨 玛拉
Hi, Marla.
- 把她留下 拿上东西到楼下等我  - 你确定吗
- Leave her with me. Get your stuff. Meet me downstairs.  - Are you sure?
是 我确定
Yes, I'm sure.
你个混球 你玩儿的是他妈什么变态游戏
You fucker! What kind of sick fucking game are you playing at,
让我他妈的 天哪 你的脸
putting me on a fucking... Oh, my God, your face!
嗯 我知道
Yeah, I know.
- 发生什么了  - 别问
- What happened?  - Don't ask.
- 你中枪了  - 是的 我中枪了  - 老天啊
- You're shot.  - Yes, I'm shot.  - Oh, my God.
- 不敢相信他还能站着  - 真他妈强悍
- I can't believe he's standing.  - Tough motherfucker.
是谁干的
Who did this?
其实是我自己干的
I did, actually.
找点儿纱布来
Find some gauze.
- 你开枪打了你自己  - 对 但没事的 玛拉 看着我
- You shot yourself?  - Yes, but it's OK. Marla, look at me.
我真的没事
I'm really OK.
相信我 一切都会好起来的
Trust me. Everything's gonna be fine.
你我相遇在我人生最诡异的时候
You met me at a very strange time in my life.
摇滚乐队Pixies的另类单曲<Where is my mind>
*脚悬空中 脑顶地上 将世界颠倒*
*With your feet on the air and your head on the ground*
*试试看吧 然后旋转起来*
*Try this trick and spin it*
*耶*
*Yeah*
*你的脑袋会崩塌*
*Your head will collapse*
"终极香烟烙印" 即将出现
*却发现里面空空如也*
*But there's nothing in it*
*你扪心自问*
*And you'll ask yourself*
*我的思想去哪儿了*
*Where is my mind*
电波字幕组 欢迎您的加入
官方网站:www.dbfansub.com
新浪微博:@电波字幕组
*逃离水中的办法*
*Way out in the water*
*看似是游泳*
*See it swimming*
*我在加勒比海遨游*
*I was swimming in the Caribbean*
*动物们都藏在石头后面*
*Animals were hiding behind a rock*
*小鱼儿们除外*
*Except the little fish*
*但他们告诉我 他发誓说*
*But they told me, he swears*
*努力地跟我交谈 跟我交谈*
*Trying to talk to me to me to me*
*我的思想去哪儿了*
*Where is my mind*
*逃离水中的办法*
*Way out in the water*
*看似是游泳*
*See it swimming*
*脚悬空中 脑顶地上 将世界颠倒*
*With your feet on the air and your head on the ground*
*试试看吧 然后旋转起来*
*Try this trick and spin it*
*耶*
*Yeah*
*你的脑袋会崩塌*
*Your head will collapse*
*却发现里面空空如也*
*But there's nothing in it*
*你扪心自问*
*And you'll ask yourself*
*我的思想去哪儿了*
*Where is my mind*
*逃离水中的办法*
*Way out in the water*
*看似是游泳*
*See it swimming*
*脚悬空中 脑顶地上 将世界颠倒*
*With your feet in the air and your head on the ground*
*试试看吧 然后旋转起来*
*Try this trick and spin it*